Chapter 1: The Cup

AN: the jumps in perspective, time, and space in this chapter are jarring for many people – I'll try and give this chapter a fifth rewrite when I have the time. The other chapters are considerably easier to read than this one – the second and third chapters narrow down to one narrative line with extra bits, and the fourth chapter is the continuation of that single narrative line with no extra bits.

AN/2: I post chapters on /r/rational and /r/hpmor, so check out those subreddits for discussion. I'm also planning to put this on AO4 and SpaceBattles! If you'd like to be a beta, please pm me!

######

The Universe Is An Optimisation Problem

By Eigenstation/imasentientantcolony

######

"What is your ambition?"

"To understand everything important there is to know about the universe, apply that knowledge to become omnipotent, and use that power to rewrite reality because I have some objections to the way it works now."

—Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality

######

"To understand how something works, figure out how to break it."

—Nassim Nicholas Taleb

######

CHAPTER ONE

######

DO NOT MESS WITH:

TIME,

THE STRUCTURE OF MAGIC,

OR

THE CLIMATE CONTROL SETTINGS

(UNLESS YOU HAVE PERMISSION FROM YOUR SUPERVISOR)

THANK YOU

— engraved on all stationery in the

Department of Mysteries

and completely coincidentally written

on the wall of a public loo in Leicester

######

If you want to know why the world is the way it is today, you'd need to take a trip to the Department of Mysteries. You'd also need a form signed in triplicate by the Minister of Magic, with the signatures of the Chief Thaumaturge of London, the Grand Sorcerer of the British Isles, the Chief Warlock of the Wizengamot, and – of course – the Department Director (who is a very busy man, not least due to the fact that at any given time, there are three of him walking through the Ministry's halls).

You'd have to pass through Level 0 of the Ministry, which has a pretty golden fountain and flying letters. After passing the security check, you'd descend to Level Minus One, which is populated mainly by interns working four-thousand hour weeks and people who stare at you suspiciously every now and then, paid primarily to contribute to the overall feeling of existential paranoia that pervades the Department.

Level Minus Two is the kind of floor where people ask questions like: "So tell me, does it eat human flesh?"

Level Minus Three is the kind of floor where people ask questions like: "Can we make it?"

The thing that changed the world forever, is on a raised pedestal in Level Minus Twenty-Eight surrounded by a shimmering cobweb of blue light. It's a mug - a stained, slightly cracked, ceramic mug with a list of easily-pronounceable anti-hangover Charms printed on the side, along with its former owner's name (misspelt), filled with what looks like glowing vanilla ice cream.

As you descend the stairs, Albus Dumbledore, the Chief Warlock will tell you that the ordinary background magic concentration in, say, Wales – is around 0.0001 thaums per cubic centimetre. He'll also tell you that within the body tissue of a wizard, it's five thaums per cubic centimetre, and that up until 1931, the highest magic concentration ever recorded had been in the central locus of the Cup of Dawn when Merlin created the Interdict – about one hundred million thaums per cubic centimetre.

At this point, curiosity piqued, you'd naturally ask him: "How many thaums per cubic centimetre does the cup have?"

To which he would respond: "Around ten to the forty-one."

This is the unimaginatively-named Cup of Magic. It was created when a Junior Unspeakable named Reginald Rookwood sneezed during an experimental ritual to turn water into whiskey in 1931, and in doing so, knocked out every electrical grid in the Northern Hemisphere for four hours, permanently melted an entire Ministry corridor, caused an electrical storm to form over a corner store in Diagon Alley, and created a new island in the North Sea. Some people say it broke magic and doomed wizardkind forever, but over the sixty-three years between then and now, the Cup of Magic has powered over six hundred and eighty thousand rituals, several of which involved creating objects with a larger mass than the Moon and had to be conducted entirely in outer space.

The rippling consequences of the existence of the Cup of Magic, in part, is why tomatoes grow on Venus, why the Soviet Union controls Hawai'i, why Hermione blew up a skyscraper when she was twelve, why Harry Potter is a mind-clone of Tom Riddle, why Ozland Dwimmersmith was born, and why the world will probably end on April 14, 1996. But before we get ahead of ourselves, it would also probably be a good idea to quickly cover the events that occurred in the years before 1994, which is when everything really begins.

And there's one more thing Albus Dumbledore will probably tell you. He'll tell you about leylines, about how wizards, with appropriate permission, can request for a new leyline to draw magic from the Cup for Ministry-approved rituals.

He'll tell you the strands of blue light are leylines, spreading out through time and space.

He's lying.

They're cracks.

######

ALBUS DUMBLEDORE – THE WIZENGAMOT – 1983 - ELEVEN YEARS BEFORE THE PRESENT DAY

" . . . achoo, ahem – as I was saying – a Muggleborn by the name of Edward Rotford, who received a 'Troll' marking on all six of his subjects, and was later expelled due to . . . "

You'd think winning a civil war would strengthen your political influence.

" . . . extraordinary waste of Ministry resources . . . "

You'd think losing a civil war would weaken it.

" . . . universally abysmal, naturally – owing to their dubious heritage . . ."

Many did, and they were wrong on both counts.

" . . . why, here — allow me to ask the Headmaster himself. Pray, if you would, Mister Dumbledore, how many Muggleborn students sat their NEWT examinations last year?"

"Sixteen. Regardless – "

"Mr Dumbledore, another question, if you see fit to answer. How many Muggleborn Hogwarts students passed their NEWT examinations last year?"

"Had they been properly schooled – "

"The unembellished answer, Lords and Ladies, is three. Three of sixteen. And of those three, only one received marks above 'Acceptable'."

An excited hubbub immediately followed.

In truth, Voldemort had not stood against magical Britain. He had disrupted the prevailing order in the same way that pelting rain disrupts the mirrored surface of a puddle, while ultimately turning that puddle into a much bigger puddle. The Death Eaters (among their ranks many aristocrats and blood-supremacists) had represented nothing more than the radical movement for a more extreme status quo.

However distorted and skewed, it was the illustration that appeared in the Daily Prophet on June 19, 1968, that most accurately encapsulated the sentiments of the British magical ruling-class. The illustration looked like this: to the right, was a muscled Amelia Bones, wrenching a screaming Abraxas Malfoy by the lapels, in the act of throwing him into a freshly-dug grave. To the left, was Bartemius Crouch, occasionally winking at the reader as he chiselled the word "NOBILITY" onto a gravestone. Looming above them all, stood Albus Dumbledore, with impassioned froth and spittle geysering from his wrinkled lips, waving about the commanding finger of octogenarian authority. "FOR THE GREATER GOOD!" read the speech-bubble emerging from his mouth.

It was a little on the nose, even by the standards of the Prophet.

It seemed that the Ministry and the hallowed halls of the Wizengamot could do nothing, for Dumbledore and his allies occupied all the most important Ministry posts, and had the sympathetic ears of many seats in both the guilds of the Mysterium and the hereditary seats of the Magisterium. He held the Line of Merlin, which could be passed on only in death (and it would be difficult if not impossible to kill Albus Dumbledore), and to rob him of the position of Chief Warlock by vote alone would have been a political impossibility.

Centuries of tradition, of accumulated power and wealth, were threatened with existential destruction.

Tom Riddle, in retrospect, had stepped in at exactly the right time.

And although his most fervent supporters had been imprisoned in Azkaban, the foundation of his rule had remained unchallenged.

"I remind the Lords and Ladies convened," enunciated Augusta Longbottom, "that this Act was passed in a year in which many members of the esteemed Wizengamot were, in fact, Death Eaters using Polyjuice. Or simply Death Eaters." She left a long pause, during which many people looked like they were about to say something, and then slyly added: "Under the Imperius, of course." Then: "Although, it appears that those selfsame Lords and Ladies continue to defend the policies crafted by none other than Volde – "

"Madam Longbottom, you forget yourself!"

And the debate raged on, although with every rhetorical parry and blow, it became clearer and clearer to Albus Dumbledore, and those who sided with him, that this battle had been lost.

" . . . accidental magic!"

" . . . rather rude, a terrible influence on my boy . . . "

The most powerful mage in Britain stood. Silence followed instantly.

Dumbledore was not smiling, nor did his eyes twinkle. Such things were reserved for Hogwarts, for the children.

"To the Wizengamot, I restate these unadorned facts in the hope that in these final few minutes of contemplation, you shall find yourself erring on the side of sympathy for all children born with Merlin's gift, leaving aside the circumstances of their parentage.

"Wizarding children born to magical parents are permitted to practice wanded magic from the age of nine. They are furthermore permitted to attend private academies and receive private tuition from this age onwards. At the age of eleven, they are permitted to attend Hogwarts, and receive five years of formal tuition. This is known to you."

There were various nods from his faction, but most of the purple robes were indifferent.

"Yet wizarding children born to non-magical, or negligibly-magical parents, are barred from knowledge of magic – likewise, attendance at Hogwarts – until their fifth year. They receive, at most, three years of tuition. First-generation wizards, quite simply, receive less in the way of education. Is it no small wonder that their academic performances are poorer than those with the benefit of magical backgrounds? Do you not conflate cause with effect?"

"Foolish old man," someone murmured.

Dumbledore looked sharply at him, and the man shrunk under his gaze, but it had been said and heard.

A few final words were exchanged, a final vote was called, and there were some hands in the air, but not enough.

Not nearly enough.

Among the Lords and Ladies aligned with Lucius Malfoy's faction were many condescending smiles, as the final vote was tallied against the proposal of Albus Dumbledore, the Chief Warlock.

"By the ruling of the twenty-first session of the one-hundred-and-ninety-fifth Wizengamot, §11.1a of Article V of the Muggleborn Safety Act of 1977, shall not be repealed."

######

"...incomplete nature of the ritual. Wanagathan 1973 made the claim that 'ach' (falling, inflected, no emphasis, heavily aspirated) - the ending symbol commonly used in most transformation-type rituals made by intermediate-novices (see Egy 1927, Aschelter 1936) in lieu of dynamic redundancy - followed by 'oo' (standard) is a multiplicative combination which could continually reinforce ambient magic until dismissed by an exhalation symbol. We respond to this claim by reminding Wanagathan that actual sneezes are very rarely vocalized as 'achoo' - they are instead violent outbursts of air which do not correspond to the phonologies of most languages. Instead, we believe the unique product of the Rookwood Whiskey Ritual could be explained precisely by the presence of this 'out of bound' sneezing symbol, which could potentially disrupt the matrix alignment of previous symbols, shifting certain rows by unit one in any of twenty-eight possible directions, according to our calculations in this paper. Rookwood himself suffering memory-loss after the magical explosion, and most of the original ritual being irrecoverable, we believe, having analysed the fragmentary evidence that exists, there is a possibility that the ritual was of a particularly dangerous form-substance-form type that involved the transformation of water into pure magic, and then back into whiskey, with the form-to-substance transformation occurring outside of temporal-spatial boundaries. Proceeding from this, the introduction of an 'out of bound' symbol may have prevented the substance-to-form transformation from fully completing, leaving only pure magic in a metastable state (enabled by its sheer density). This hypothesis would elegantly explain all observations concerning the Cup of Magic as recorded by Kagnarr 1932."

Extract from the Journal of the Cyprian Thaumaturgical Research Society (pg. 103, Vol. 22)

######

TOM RIDDLE – BORGIN AND BURKES, KNOCKTURN ALLEY, INSIDE AN EXPANDED POCKET OF INTERDIMENSIONAL SPACE, LONDON – 1949, FORTY-FIVE YEARS BEFORE THE PRESENT-DAY

Tom Riddle (who was not yet Lord Voldemort) was on his way to solving two people's problems at once. The first problem was that the majority shareholder of Colossan Trust, Walter Rockefeller, wanted a powerful wizard to protect Tibbles – his cat – from harm. All harm. He'd described it like this: "Mr Riddle – if Tibbles gets thrown into the Sun, I want the Sun to be the one who comes off worst."

The second problem was that the British government needed someone who could deal with the IRA. And by 'deal with', they really meant it. With the quotation marks and everything. In official governmentspeak, it was: "We wouldn't condone a genocide, Riddle, but the British community will understand perfectly well if more severe measures are necessary to end this war on a permanent basis."

If you can't see a way to solve both of these problems and make money at the same time, you're probably not Tom Riddle.

But the solution to those two problems created a third problem for him: there weren't any rituals which could actually create over a million Horcruxes at once, and probably even less that could make them for a cat.

On the other hand, Tom knew that he could probably figure one out by the end of his shift.

"What's that, Tom?"

He was startled from his reverie by Caractacus Burke, the obnoxious owner of the store. Burke was rarely interested in the fascinating items that came in and went out of his store, only in ensuring that jingly gold coins mostly went in one of those directions. He had a thick, greasy moustache which, if wrung out over a frying pan, would probably provide enough oil to make French toast with. Burke's manner was stooped, thinly curious, intruding, and his breath smelt like horseradish and turpentine.

Tom silently vowed that, after all of it was over, he would kill Burke very quickly and efficiently, not because he deserved any reprise from a painful death, but because he wasn't worth more than a half-second of Tom's time.

"It's a diagram of a sacrificial runic circle designed to kill everyone inside of it, turn their corpses into Horcruxes, and shoot the corpses into space at a hundred kilometres a second," was what he badly wanted to say. Instead, he said: "It's a diagram of a runic circle designed to stabilise volatile potions, sir."

"Interesting, very interesting," Burke breathed, his eyes gleaming, "I used to dabble in that kind of thing. How does it work?"

Tom fired off a long stream of made-up runic-ritual sounding words and inwardly sighed every time Burke gave a shrewd nod, as if he actually understood.

"Well now, I think that might just work," he said after Tom had finished.

"I'm not quite sure it will, sir," Tom replied, "so I'm visiting a runician in Ulster who might be able to help me work out the details. Although there is another purpose to my visit - I believe he also has a fragment of the original Cup of Dawn."

"Oh yes?"

"Indeed, sir. I'm thinking I'll pay a little more than necessary to get his cooperation on my runic circle designs and maybe I'll - "

"Ah, I don't think that will be strictly necessary, Tom. That's not how you negotiate these things. A fragment of the original Cup of Dawn, you say?"

"Yes, sir," Tom gritted out.

Caractacus Burke stroked his chin. "Well, what say you I come with? When's it?"

"Oh, it'll be a month or two at the very least. He's a very busy man."

"I'll make the preparations. Let me know once you have an exact date, Tom. Very good work."

Tom Riddle always did everything perfectly, so nobody saw him carve deep, jutting lines into the grounds around every Republican stronghold in Ireland - and the people who did, didn't remember. The late forties were the golden age of new rituals, and the Cup of Magic was not yet under lock and key on Level Minus Twenty-Eight of the Ministry basement, so nobody was especially suspicious when an enterprising young man, fresh out of Hogwarts, filled in the form requesting for a few new leylines so he could draw magic from the Cup. Even when those leylines were mysteriously extended by a few thousand kilometers, the only thing people thought was mysterious about him was his relationship status.

On December 10, 1949, when there was a deafening supersonic bang that was heard from Nova Scotia to beyond the Ural Mountains, when three point eight million people were suddenly missing, and when a cat and a certain Tom Riddle were suddenly very immortal indeed, nobody suspected the boy at the counter of Borgin and Burkes.

By six o'clock, after stopping by Walter Rockefeller's mansion in California, he was about two metric tonnes of gold wealthier.

By eight o'clock, after meeting a shady man in a Scottish corner-street, he had about eighty million pounds worth of government bonds.

By nine o'clock, he was bored again.

By ten o'clock, after rearranging his name for half an hour, and staring at that day's edition of the Prophet, he'd thought of something interesting to fill up time between then and eternity.

######

The Wand

MINISTER PUGEONN WARNS AGAINST INFLUENCE OF 'REACTIONARY FANATICS'

March 9, 1968

'LORD VOLDEMORT' WANTED BY MINISTRY FOR MURDER OF JOYCE STEWART

April 28, 1969

DEATH EATERS DECLARE WAR ON BRITAIN

January 3, 1970

######

Dawning Moment Herald

PRES. LABAR RE-ELECTED TO SERVE FIFTH TERM

November 4, 1992

His Ascendancy President Labar, leader of the free world, of the Dawning Moment, of the White Race, and of Colossan Tobacco (North America), a genius unparalleled in human history, has been re-elected, as determined by the Almighty, to serve His third term as President of the United States of America. His Ascendancy won with a spectacular 84% of the popular vote, with the Dawning Moment Party winning 56 out of 60 of voting states.

######

Leaflet given out at the 1991 London Protest:

THREE TRUSTS CONTROL YOUR WORLD

— THE COLOSSAN TRUST —

— NEGALOTH INC. —

— THAUCORP INTERNATIONAL —

ARE ALL OWNED BY STANDARD HOLDINGS

& COMMANDED BY THE EXECUTIVE COUNCIL OF NINE.

THEY CONTROL WHAT YOU BUY.

THEY CONTROL WHAT YOU SEE.

THEY CONTROL WHAT YOU THINK.

THEY CONTROL YOUR LIFE.

WITHOUT ECONOMIC DEMOCRACY,

THERE IS ONLY DICTATORSHIP.

THE FREEDOM OF THE RULING-CLASS,

IS THE SLAVERY OF THE RULED.

THEY BELIEVE YOU ARE COMPLACENT.

ARE THEY WRONG?

"THOSE WHO DO NOT MOVE,

DO NOT NOTICE THEIR CHAINS."

— ROSA LUXEMBURG

######

LARGEST PRIVATE ENTITIES BY MARKET CAPITALIZATION (MARCH 1992)

1. Colossan Trust — $6.6 trillion — finance, real estate, energy, manufacturing, defense, agriculture, construction, tobacco — 67% owned by Standard Holdings

2. Negaloth Inc. — $3.8 trillion — media, telecommunications, cable & satellite, private defense, surveillance, government relations, advertising, entertainment, hospitality, transport, electronic media, debt collection — 85% owned by Standard Holdings

3. ThauCorp International — $2.1 trillion — aerospace, electronics, artificial intelligence, private education, research and development, pharmaceutical — 24% owned by Standard Holdings, 76% owned by Allan Unnman

—The Eagle (March 19, 1992)

######

We commemorate this monument to Anita Gadberry, a primary-school student among the three hundred whose lives were violently foreshortened in this very London square, murdered by the Negaloth Private Defense Corps in the May Protest of 1991.

May she be forever remembered.

—Gadberry Monument

######

HERMIONE GRANGER – DR DAVID WILLIGAN'S THERAPEUTIC PSYCHIATRY CENTRE, BALHAM, SOUTH LONDON, UNITED KINGDOM – MAY 4, 1992 - TWO YEARS BEFORE THE PRESENT-DAY

One thousand soldiers face an advancing mob, resolute.

A bottle spirals, turns three times, and shatters.

In a second, gunfire fills the air.

Blood spills out in litres, and someone screams a word.

Blood spills out in litres, and someone screams a word.

Blood spills out in litres, and someone screams a word.

"Hermione?"

The girl snapped back to attention in an instant. "Yes, sir?"

"If you don't mind, Hermione, I'd like to know what's on your mind." He paused to gauge her reaction, but her face remained impassive, as always. "I know you find these sessions annoying, but your parents are worried about you. I'd like to be able to assuage their concerns."

"Don't all parents worry about their children?"

He ignored her and continued. "Your school counsellor is also worried." Usually he would try and empathise with his patients – making light conversation. Unfortunately, Hermione Granger invariably managed to divert the conversation far away from talk of her wellbeing or mental health, until the one-hour session expired and he went home, immensely frustrated. He hadn't even been aware of it the first few times. This time, Doctor Willigan noticed, she had offered him only a half-hearted diversion. There was something she wanted to say, and he'd be damned if he knew what it was.

"Oh?"

"She's somewhat disturbed at how well you've been . . . coping. Managing the trauma of losing someone close to you. She says you seem to be barely affected. She thinks you're channeling your . . . anguish into academic performance, however silly that may sound."

She lightly tapped her finger on her cheek.

Plock.

Plock.

Plock.

"Is that necessarily a bad thing, Mister Willigan?"

He momentarily choked. " . . . what?"

"Because most of the adults I know are pretty transparently driven by feelings of sexual inadequacy, fears of never attaining eminence or distinction, desire for status in highly competitive hierarchical environments, anxiety from failure to sufficiently conform to social norms . . . but I could name hundreds of scientists, engineers, and authors who were driven to greatness by traumatic deaths – "

"I – "

She continued as if he hadn't spoken. " – Harold Milton's mother passed away in 1974 when he was an undergrad at Ohio State University, after which he successfully developed the prototype whale-milk-hydrocarbon conversion method, and solved the energy crisis . . . in Memoirs, Eula Kovach cited her anguish over the death of her fiancée as a large part of her motivation to write the fifty-million-word long Godflesh series — Gilderoy Locker attributed his meteoric rise from Negaloth public relations consultant to a member of the Executive Council of Nine to rejection from his hometown. I could go on, but I think I've made my point."

That was prepared. And I was the one leading the conversation. "Your point?" The most frustrating thing about having Hermione Granger as his patient was that she clammed up. And when he prised her mind open, he would inevitably find another clam. An infinite set of delicately-constructed selves, with not a single slip or loss of composure. Levels and levels and layers and layers of paper-wrapping and colourful ribbons and strange loops.

But there was a fiery determination that shone through her eyes, and that was something she could never hide.

"Maybe I am channeling my anguish. Isn't that better than burying it? I read the books you recommended to me last time." All of them? Should he have been surprised? "I know it's bad to hide your emotions, they just end up . . . bubbling up somewhere else when you least expect it. I'm turning thirteen next month, Doctor. It's been almost a whole year since Anita died. At least I'm steering it somewhere constructive."

Willigan was curious. "Somewhere constructive?"

"I'm going to med school. I'm going to be a dentist. Just like my parents. And nothing is going to stop me."

######

She was lying.

She was building a bomb.

######

THE ONE WITH THE POWER TO VANQUISH THE DARK LORD APPROACHES,

BORN TO THOSE WHO HAVE THRICE DEFIED HIM,

BORN AS THE SEVENTH MONTH DIES,

AND THE DARK LORD WILL MARK HIM AS HIS EQUAL,

BUT HE WILL HAVE POWER THE DARK LORD KNOWS NOT,

AND EITHER MUST DESTROY ALL BUT A REMNANT OF THE OTHER,

FOR THOSE TWO DIFFERENT SPIRITS CANNOT EXIST IN THE SAME WORLD.

—Sybill Trelawney, 1980

######

HE IS HERE. THE ONE WHO WILL TEAR APART THE VERY STARS IN HEAVEN.

HE IS HERE. HE IS THE END OF THE WORLD.

—Sybill Trelawney, 1991

######

THE TOWER AND THE GODDESS SEND CHARIOTS OF FIRE INTO THE SKY, AND END THE EARTH IN THEIR WAKE.

—Telesphorus Eastrodor, 1865

######

SHE, THE FIRSTE DOGHTER OF THE SEOFENTHE SONE, AND THE ONSE AND FUȝERE KING MARCDE BY LYTENNING, SHAL CROSSEN THE BRITTISH SOUȝTH SE, AND BEREN A BEBLEEDYN CROWYNE.

—Taciturna Trelawney, 1317

######

GOLD BECOMES LEAD, AS LEAD BECOMES GOLD.

—Golofor Yammabagus, 1799

######

ALL ENDINGS SHALL BE ENDED BY THE CRUX.

—Augerna Hrosdóttir, 188 (first recorded prophecy in Britain)

######

FEBRUARY 26, 1993 - THE BOY-WHO-LIVED

Harry James Potter Evans-Verres fixed things.

He fixed faulty taps, fractured windscreens, ripped books, and wrecked umbrellas. Nothing electronic, nothing capable of recording anything, and with one caveat: you weren't allowed to watch.

"No seams . . . nothing. Where on Earth did you learn your craft, Harry? Ten pounds, wasn't it?"

"That's right, Mrs Figg," Harry replied politely.

"Come in, come in. Snowy, please make some room for our guest, here."

A malicious-looking cat looked up at him briefly from a chintz armchair, and stayed resolutely put.

"Don't mind him, Harry, it's his – "

"Favourite chair, yes, I remember."

She beamed at him, and tottered out of the room, presumably to search for her wallet.

"You know," Harry said, addressing Snowy, "if you get out of that chair, I'll leave mince for you out to the side of the driveway again. Fair?"

The cat flicked its ears.

"Two fifty grams."

The cat flicked its ears again.

" . . . five hundred."

The cat did a cat-yawn.

"Six hundred with a few shavings of ham, final offer . . . ah, that did it."

He was perfectly fine standing around for a couple of minutes while Mrs Figg fetched her wallet – but then again, this was another opportunity to negotiate with a breed of sentient cats.

When Harry was twelve, the world had changed.

He was in the kitchen while his parents were out, decided all of a sudden that he wanted to make chocolate biscuits, and in the process, accidentally dropped his parents' wedding bowl, shattering it into hundreds of porcelain shards. He closed his eyes, quickly counted to ten in his head, snapped his fingers, and it suddenly wasn't shattered. It lay there on the floor, quite whole and untampered with.

He failed to replicate this result with another bowl, and attributed it to lack of sleep.

Then three days later, he quickly counted to ten, snapped his fingers, and watched as glass fragments dragged themselves across the carpet and sealed themselves together into a wine glass.

Then two days after that, he noticed a bar called the Leaky Cauldron jutting out along Charing Cross Road.

Gradually, Harry came to the realization that his map, carefully drawn with reference to Feynman and Einstein, Newton and Jopasfeld, no longer matched the territory.

Onetwothreefourfivesixseveneightnineten –

Snap.

And there was magic.

######

Oxford, United Kingdom, Prime Material Plane

She came not at the thirteenth hour, but at 2am on a motorbike. She came with the low gleams of twenty street-lamps on her obsidian visor, with her worn leather jacket flailing in the windy tempest, with clinically-utilitarian grey platform boots planted on the welcome mat, and a slightly cracked voice. She came with a faded We Are Cosmic Nomads Tour of 1989 band shirt and a bold, confident gait.

Knock knock, went the door to Harry's workshop.

Harry looked up from his book, carefully noted down the page, closed the book, placed the book into the shelf, and approached the door.

Knock knock knock, went the door once more.

He looked through the peephole and saw the black mirror of a biking helmet.

"It's two in the morning," he said.

"Your lights are on," came the crisp reply.

Estuary accent. "You saw the ad?"

"That I did."

"You're a sentimental biker with a wocked-up part from an obsolete make and no one else so far's been able to fix it?"

A long pause from the other end. "Well, yeah," she sounded amused. "You're a smart boy." (Harry suppressed the brief wave of irritation that followed this remark.) "Mhm, could I come in now? It's a little cold out here, and I have a concert to get to, so . . . "

He unlocked the door, and she strode inside, accompanied by a strong gust. "What band?" he asked conversationally, closing the door after her.

"Septic Glow." The stranger's gaze, still under the visor, wandered around his workshop, and remained at a long row of books before jerking away to face him. "Nice set-up."

"Thanks."

"Alright, so . . . it wasn't in the ad, but the word is . . . well, okay – can you really fix anything in under ten minutes, or was that just a gimmick?"

Harry slowly shook his head, grinning. "Not a gimmick. Usually it's under five, but I say ten just to be safe. What's it you need fixed?"

The voice from under the dome was laced with skepticism. "It's a customized ThauMobile 10386 F-class pneumatic-grapple modulator, and if you can fix it in under five minutes . . . call the Satanic Society and give them your address because I already tried God and he didn't do shit."

"I doubt they'd be interested in an ordinary industrial process."

She held out a ziplock bag, containing granules of metal, bits of plastic, crushed pipes, and two neatly bifurcated halves of an intricate pre-1979 modulator. "Does your ordinary industrial process work with this?"

Harry took the bag, and made a show of examining it. "Is this everything?"

"Huh?"

"No missing stuff?"

"Nope, all there." She wrung her hands. "The, ah, bike's been my dad's for twenty years. I had to borrow my boyfriend's cruiser to get here, just doesn't feel the same, you know? Nothing short of witchcraft will fix this crap."

Heh, witchcraft. He looked back up at her. "Right, okay. I can repair this in a couple of minutes, maybe four tops. I'll need you to wait outside, for a couple of minutes while I do this."

"Alright," the stranger said slowly. "How come?"

"Eh, it's a tradition. Or an old charter. Or something. Besides, I wouldn't want you to see all the sacrificial lambs I'm slaughtering."

"Septic did that at their last gig," she murmured idly. "What's this deal, then?" She pointed at a monitor that continually spat out a long stream of numbers.

"Personal hobby. Don't you have a concert to get to?"

"It's twenty minutes away," and then in a quieter voice, "twenty two seven zero one five . . . "

"Hmm?"

The woman seemed to struggle with herself before continuing to speak. "This is emulating a Trust relay-terminal. That's illegal. And impossible."

Harry shrugged. "I can neither confirm nor deny – "

She batted her hand dismissively. "I'm not going to dob you in." She stopped. "Oh, I see now. You . . . that's clever."

Bluff?

"Alright, I'll tell you what I know. They have these in factories to rapidly send production stats to the Colossan Executive Monitor through the Mundial network. But," she said, walking still closer to the monitor, "you've meshed into the Mundial by spoofing a non-allocated factory space. And you're sending botched stats. But . . . why?"

"Well . . . "

"This isn't just random data, isn't it?"

Another ten second pause.

And then she started humming the national anthem.

Harry froze. "What – "

She laughed, and it wasn't a cold laugh or a condescending laugh, or even a mean laugh – it was a genuine, relaxed laugh. "It's in the barcodes. Don't worry, it's not obvious. That's what I first noticed, you see? The last eight digits. 00286531, 01583921, 500000, 00291111, etcetera etcetera. Audio encoding, isn't it? Then based on the first five notes, it was either the national anthem or the third bar of Der Himmel in C, and – "

"You're observant."

The stranger reeled back slightly. "I did a multiplex networking degree in uni. And my dad is middle-management at a steel refinery, so I know about this stuff."

Hmm. "Will you tell?"

"I said, I'm not going to dob you in. Is there, ah, another spoofed terminal receiving the data?"

Harry gestured at the back of the room. "Under the big white sheet. I trust you realize the implications?"

"Um, we won't have to wait hours to get mail on the Echo, so practically instantaneous text communications, ah, maybe instant image – hey, what's the bitrate like?"

He grimaced. "Two kilobits a second, if I max it out and do double-encoding with the temperature readings. With anything else, they always catch on and I have to – "

" – start it all over again, right."

There was a long, awkward silence, probably made more awkward by the impassive black visor, from which his mammalian hindbrain tried desperately to recover some semblance of social cues and ended up with total ambiguity.

He coughed. "Your modulator, by the way."

"Uh-huh?" She still seemed to be in deep thought.

Harry held it up to eye-level. "It would usually be fifty pounds for something mechanical, but I'll make it thirty for breaking up my boredom."

"I – wait, what? Give me that."

Obligingly, he chucked the bag to her.

She opened it up and held the completely-undamaged ThauMobile 10386 F-class pneumatic-grapple modulator. "No – you, I . . . this . . . "

"Yes, I, you, that?"

"It's even got . . . " she blew through a nozzle jutting out of the top, and a clear note rang out. "Well fuck me," she counted out three notes, and handed them to Harry, "I would've bet anything against this getting . . . well, I would have accused you of having a duplicate and switching them around – but I, ah, added on a few things, and they're still there, so, well, okay." She shook her head. "I'm not even going to try. I'll try and figure out how you gamed the verification protocol for connecting to the Mundial, but this – I, wow. You'll go places. What are you planning? You know, career-wise. "

Harry nodded. "I'm not sure. But I've got a checklist."

"What's on it?"

He took a deep breath. "It's a list I made when I was eleven: meeting all the interesting people in the world, reading all the good books and then writing something even better, celebrating my first grandchild's tenth birthday party on the Moon, celebrating my first great-great-great grandchild's hundredth birthday party around the Rings of Saturn, learning the deepest and final rules of Nature, understanding the nature of consciousness, finding out why anything exists in the first place, visiting other stars, discovering aliens, creating aliens, rendezvousing with everyone for a party on the other side of the Milky Way once we've explored the whole thing, and meeting up with everyone else who was born on Old Earth to watch the Sun finally go out."

"Really? That's ambitious." The stranger looked at her watch. "I'm going to be a dentist."

Harry stared back at her with total incomprehension.

She pocketed the ziplock bag, walked to the door, and unlocked it. "Anyway, thanks for the repair. And, ah, an interesting conversation."

"Before you go – I forgot to ask, what's your name?"

######

EXPLOSIONS DEVASTATE NEGALOTH TOWERS

May 7, 1993

A wave of devastating attacks struck several Negaloth-owned buildings today in central London. The Negaloth Financial Services Complex was destroyed "in a manner resembling ... controlled demolition", while the Negaloth Telephone Tower caught fire, with the building exploding level by level after most personnel had been evacuated. Several banks, malls, and internal coordination centres were also severely damaged, rendering them inoperable for "at least two years". About 382 people are confirmed to have perished in the attacks, although analysts say that had the attacks been planned even slightly differently, or carried out tomorrow rather than Labour Day – the death toll would have been in the high thousands – suggesting an intent to financially cripple Negaloth rather than petty terrorism. Experts say that the attacks were likely carried out by a hostile foreign entity with enormous access to resources, involved up to one thousand people, and were likely planned over the course of twenty to thirty years. They have suggested that the attacks may have been carried out by the IRA, the Stasi, or Welsh separatists – or potentially a combination of these organizations.

######

"God, it was like a balloon - kept inflating till the skin was all stretched and white and taut and then - pop - it exploded with guts and blood and bullets, just pouring out onto the street."

######

STONEFIELDS, AUCKLAND, NEW ZEALAND – OCTOBER 18, 1981 - FOURTEEN YEARS BEFORE THE PRESENT DAY

"Do you remember now, Mr Cunningham?"

A baby carriage was by the door.

"I do remember now," spoke Humphrey, "how very odd – must be my medication, I don't get lapses like this very often. Rosie!"

A harried-looking blonde woman in her dressing gown flounced down the stairs and glared at the two oddly-dressed people by the door. "Wossit?"

"It's our son, dear, these officers found him – "

His wife sniffed. "What on Earth are you on about? We don't have a – "

"Somnium," said the man.

"Levicorpus," said the woman.

And in a fraction of a second, his wife was hoisted into the air by her ankles, seemingly fast asleep.

"You – "

He knew he should have been boiling with rage. Whatever new crowd-control device this was, they were both paying alumni of the Silver Horde and shouldn't be treated like that – but as soon as it coalesced, the anger dissipated, drained out, like water from a punctured bucket, and Humphrey Cunningham stood on the marble tiles of the waiting room with a strange, empty sense of calm.

And then his brain caught up to him, and he realized his wife was floating.

"Wha – "

With another muttered word from the two officers, his jaw was suddenly clamped shut. His arms, however much he struggled, were completely paralysed, were locked at his sides. His legs similarly refused to move.

He watched, as the woman walked, in slow, measured footsteps, over to his wife, whose upside-down frame hovered in the chill air. She brought out a stick, and tapped it on Rosie's forehead. Her eyes rolled open with a greasy sound – deadened, dull, and fast asleep.

Demons.

Humphrey was a singularly unsuperstitious man, but now didn't seem to be the time for rational thought either.

The woman stared into her eyes for several long minutes. "Should be fine," she said finally. Then she twitched the stick, and this time, at the end of the stick, there was a pale shimmer, which slowly draped itself over his wife like a ghostly jellyfish.

She stood in that position, seeming to do nothing at all, eyelids shut, for half an hour, before the man spoke.

"Astrava, we should leave."

The woman's head jerked upward. "We're outside of the Ministry wards, darling. And I doubt any Death Eaters will be here. We can afford to add a few more memories for the sake of our son." The man nodded, seeming to acquiesce, and then a few minutes later, with a look of immense satisfaction, the woman unruffled her cloak, and stood up to leave. She directed her stick at him. "Finite Incantatem." Humphrey felt his body relax and untense, and twiddled his fingers experimentally.

"I – "

The man approached him with an unreadable expression. "Look after little Oz, won't you? Obliviate."

(fleeting disorientation)

" . . . and you'd better keep an eye on him next time, he's a very frisky young lad."

"Of course," his wife replied smoothly. "Goodnight, officers."

"Night," he croaked after them, although he wasn't sure why his voice felt so strained.

######

AUGUST 26, 1995 - TABLE 19, DENNY'S FAMILY RESTAURANT, AUCKLAND, NEW ZEALAND

In a different era, Ozland Cunningham would be surrounded by angry Christians with burning torches. Instead, by 1995, he was the de facto leader of a small country and a doomsday New Age religion, filled with non-angry Christians who burnt things that made them less angry. Jesus could turn water into wine - Oz could turn water into very soupy grapefruit juice. While President Labar could purportedly raise the dead, Oz could raise a (light) pen about eight centimetres off a table. His miracles were small, but they were real, and they were all that the Celestial Unorthodox Church needed to draw in new followers, declare a new Messiah, and gun down everyone who disagreed.

Life was good. Everything was going according to schedule.

Until suddenly, it stopped going according to schedule.

Every morning the acting government (the Auckland Authority of the Celestial Unorthodox Church) would assemble around a greasy diner table and have pot noodles. At the table that day was Evelyn Matchwell, Domovan Kim, and Ozland Cunningham. Missing at the table were Kevin O'Hammon, and Rushabh - their formal leader, also a reclusive drug lord and an insane megalomaniac who brought peace to Auckland by threatening to detonate a nuclear bomb.

Evelyn was nineteen, tall and blonde, with all the grace and poise of a living Greek statue and dazzling white teeth. She had a knock-off British accent, and there was a refined sharpness to her - almost as if every flippant hand-gesture was a delicate medical operation, Ozland noticed, but it clashed with the pink heart-shaped sunglasses and the glass bottle of Coca Cola she was sipping from. She was the face of television and the voice of the radio - the daughter of St Matchwell, who founded the Celestial Unorthodox Church in 1973 - utterly, instantly recognisable. She didn't just have a cult-following - she had a cult. Ozland had even found her face printed on acid tabs.

Domovan was eighteen, with black hair slicked back to the point where his barber might as well have been a jet exhaust. He was the third son of the CEO of the Pan-Asia Four Star Hotel chain, which, naturally, had its own paramilitary and transnational crime syndicate - both of which were necessary to provide a decent hotel service in the lawless morass of unstable regimes barely propped by the United Kingdom. He inhaled through an e-cigarette like an alien who could only survive in an atmosphere of vanilla-flavoured vapor, and clouds followed in his wake like contrails from an airplane.

Ozland was younger than all of them at fifteen, and slightly shorter too - but until you'd seen them all together, you'd insist he was the tallest of them all. There wasn't anything particularly spectacular about him - he wasn't fat or thin, his face was bland and forgettable, but not too forgettable, his hair was the colour of lint from an old brown sweater, and his eyes were an indeterminate greyish-blue. Nevertheless, he was more recognisable even then Evelyn, who had long since attained cultural immortality.

"Rushabh is dead, Kevin is sulking about it, a high-ranking priest in the 77 Church defected to us at four this morning - says he was abducted by Celestians - he wants to see you . . . and an owl tried to deliver a letter to you last night," Evelyn started.

Ozland froze. "Rushabh, the owl, then the Churcher, please," he said, controlling his voice carefully.

Evelyn stopped drinking, wiped her mouth with a dotted pink handkerchief, and set down the glass. "He locked his room, and overdosed on just about everything he could find. Did you know you can overdose on pomegranate juice? The Chief of Police thinks he got impatient, tried hanging himself, and only managed to damage his throat and suffocate himself a little. Then he picked up a gun and shot himself. He missed the first time and the bullet only carved out a line on the top of his skull, so he filled up a bathtub and dropped a toaster in, but the toaster wasn't plugged into a socket so the Chief isn't sure why he did that. Then he got out of the tub, slipped on a puddle, hit his head against the side of the tub, and died pretty soon after that."

"Alright, what are you thinking, Ev?" he said, before realizing he should be more specific.

"I was thinking 'poisoned with plutonium in his Magnum ice cream by fanatics affiliated with the 77 Church', but that's a little dull."

"Magnum?" Ozland asked, still distracted.

"Can't have Tip Top complaining again," Ev said lightly.

He drummed his fingers on the table. "People call us the ice cream mafia for a reason, Ev – people notice this kind of shit after a while. That's three supposedly Magnum-related deaths in, what, three months? Hasn't Magnum already suffered enough? Why don't we just shell their factories instead of subjecting them to slow, humiliating bad publicity through falsified police reports?"

"I know," she giggled, "it's so silly how people believe whatever we tell them. Alright, you have a point there. I'll say it was a ThauNestlé cappuccino or something. And then tonight shell their factories just for a change. Anyway, as I was saying – nobody really visits Rushabh except for me, you, Dom, and Kev - we can keep this from the newspapers for a week at the most, so I'll handle the media until we can fudge the records properly."

"Also," Dom burst, clearly having wanting to have gotten in a word for some time now, "he left a note."

"Go on," said Ozland.

"His last will and testament, naming you as the heir to all of his worldly possessions."

"Huh."

Dom straightened up the miscreant papers from his cream-white dossier. "He left a vault with three expired ice-skating vouchers, his cat, a baggie of five-fifty tabs, and a signed affidavit from about four months ago stating that he firmly believes you didn't nick his car in '93, and that should evidence come to the attention of the police making you a suspect of the car-nicking, that all charges were to be dropped. Also the cat wasn't in the vault, by the way."

Ozland exhaled, leaning back into the plush, slightly sticky mint-green seat. "Why do you reckon he killed himself, Ev?"

She shrugged. The words: he was insane, although unspoken, hung heavily in the air.

"Alright, tell me about the owl."

Dom cleared his throat, preempting Evelyn. "An owl swooped in on your apartment while you were sleeping at around four this morning. My men shot it down. It had a letter with it."

"What kind of owl?"

"A fat brown one. Also not a bulletproof one."

He passed over the blood-splattered parchment. Ozland took it, unfurled it, and began to read.

"Why'd you even have to add that, Dom? It's not funny."

"It's objectively funny," Dom fired back defensively.

"Both of you – shut up, I'm trying to read this shit," Ozland snapped.

HOGWARTS SCHOOL of WITCHCRAFT and WIZARDRY

Headmaster: Albus Dumbledore

(Order of Merlin, First Class, Grand Sorc., Chf. Warlock,

Supreme Mugwump, International Confed. of Wizards,)

Dear Mr Dwimmersmith,

We are pleased to inform you that you have been accepted at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry. Please find enclosed a list of all necessary books and equipment.

Term begins on 1 September. We await your owl by no later than 31 July.

Yours sincerely,

Minerva McGonagall

Deputy Headmistress

HOGWARTS SCHOOL of WITCHCRAFT and WIZARDRY

UNIFORM

First-year students will require.

1. Three sets of plain work robes (black)

2. One plain pointed hat (black) for day wear

3. One pair of protective gloves (dragonhide or similar)

4. One winter cloak (black, with silver fastenings)

Please note that all pupil's clothes should carry name tags.

COURSE BOOKS

All students should have a copy of each of the following:

The Standard Book of Spells (Grade 1)

by Miranda Goshawk

A History of Magic

by Bathilda Bagshot

Magical Theory

by Adalbert Waffling

A Beginner's Guide to Transfiguration

by Emeric Switch

One Thousand Magical Herbs and Fungi

by Phyllida Spore

Magical Drafts and Potions

by Arsenius Jigger

Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them

by Newt Scamander

The Dark Forces: A Guide to Self-Protection

by Quentin Trimble

Basic Ritual Theory

by Invock Pentagrove

OTHER EQUIPMENT

1 wand (maximum 12)

1 cauldron (pewter, standard size 2)

1 set glass or crystal phials

1 telescope

1 set brass scales

1 set of ritual chalk

Students may also bring, if they desire, an owl OR a cat OR a toad.

PARENTS ARE REMINDED THAT FIRST YEARS

ARE NOT ALLOWED THEIR OWN BROOMSTICK

Yours sincerely,

Lucinda Thomsonicle-Pocus

Chief Attendant of Witchcraft Provisions

Then he read it again.

And again.

"Okay, I don't get it," he finally admitted. "Let's put this down for the moment and talk about the Churcher – Lord, you two – Dom, you're the general of a fucking army – Ev, you're supposed to be the Head of Propaganda for the fastest fucking growing religion in Australasia – so stop glaring at one another like fucking children."

Evelyn sarcastically poked her tongue out at Dom, but the tension was already defused.

Oz sighed and rung a bell. In under three seconds, a waiter was standing attentively at their table. He'd been hiding behind a potted plant, not entirely successfully. Oz could see the moment where he massaged his strung-out, panicked face into a pre-programmed smile. "How much will another three bowls of noodles be?"

"It's free today," the waiter said immediately.

"They always say that," Ozland muttered.

######

"I saw them, I saw them with my own damn eyes."

On the other side of a one-way mirror, the Chief of Police stood, along with Ozland Dwimmersmith and Donovan Yu.

The A.A.C.U.C Central Police Station building was a sprawling labyrinth of mottled paint, electronically-locked doors, uniformed men looking at you suspiciously, threadbare chairs, and fluorescent lights housed inside a brutalist facade that seemed to proudly declare to the world: we're unaccountable and there's not a thing you can do about it, honey.

And, unsurprisingly, deep within its intestines, a priest was recounting an alien abduction.

"Ask him what he saw," said Ozland, to the Chief.

"Ask him what he saw," said the Chief into a microspeak.

"What did you see?" asked the interrogator.

The man inside the room inside the A.A.C.U.C Central Police Station was tall and gaunt, with a blue vein popping out the side of his face, and wrinkles around his blue eyes like twisted plastic wrap. His hair was blonde but thinning. He was wearing distinctive white clerical clothing and the number 77 was emblazoned on both of the cuffs, along with a blue swastika. His name was Walter Frond, and up until recently, he was a high-ranking clergyman in the 77 Church, living in a beautiful beachside home along Long Island Road in the Mongol Territory to the south-east of Auckland. Now, he was quaking and shivering and every eight seconds his left nostril twitched nervously. Not five hours ago, he suddenly took a bus to the Auckland Central Police Station at three in the morning, and quietly defected to the Celestial Unorthodox Church.

Walter Frond paused, as if tasting the words in his mouth before saying them.

"I saw a huge fucking metal ship."

######

BILL WEASLEY - JOUGLARIE, MOUNT JOUGLARIE, CENTRAL LOWLANDS, SCOTLAND - FEBRUARY 8, 1992

Bill Weasley was looking over a set of ornate, teardrop-shaped stones, when the ground beneath him rattled and Dumbledore suddenly stumbled into his field of vision.

"Oh, hello there, Bill! These mountainquakes are something, aren't they?" Dumbledore said very offhandedly. "A little unusual, don't you think?"

"What's your angle?" Bill replied rather tersely, then cursed under his breath, "I'm sorry about my tone, Headmaster, I lost my rune finger . . . " he instinctively searched for a jargon-less way to explain it, but quickly remembered that he was talking to Albus Dumbledore, the legendary war-hero who transplanted the entirety of Diagon Alley into a parallel universe during the Wizarding War, who probably knew twice what Bill did about his own damn job and then some, "in a 3rd degree interface-splinch when the gravitational alignment of the mountain fluxed the SA-barrier - probably because of the mountainquakes actually," he continued fluidly. Bill held up a blood-soaked bandage for emphasis. "I'm still a little ticked-off, sorry for being impolite just then."

Dumbledore simply looked amused that Bill had gone to the trouble of apologising, he hadn't seemed too offended. The old wizard hummed a little, examining the teardrop stones, and then, as if remembering something, jolted a little. "Bill, would you be willing to take on an apprentice?"

Bill stopped. "What?"

"An apprentice - a Muggleborn - well, not quite Muggleborn per se, but Muggle-raised, if you will, who will be entering into Hogwarts for his Fifth Year, around three years from now."

There were a lot of things Bill found confusing about that sentence.

The old wizard sighed. "Again, I find myself saying too little and meaning too much. Would you care to join me for a walk outside?"

Dumbfounded, and a little curious, Bill followed him out of the front door of Randallana's Ritualist Rarities, finding himself in the middle of an early-morning mist, punctuated every few metres by black streetlamps. The streets of Jouglarie were cold and deserted. It was fairly ordinary-looking - Bill could almost believe it was a Muggle neighbourhood, apart from the fact that it was all built vertically on the side of a mountain. He stared upward, and although the sight was ordinary to him now, there was something perpetually astounding about seeing the rolling green hills of Scotland perpendicular to the ground. "So," he said, gathering his thoughts. "I hope I don't come off as rude, but mind telling me what this is about?"

As always, there was a long, contemplative pause before Dumbledore responded. "I read something rather curious in a back edition of the Journal of the Cyprian Thaumaturgical Research Society - a study produced by Lann Johnson and Gamil Aknaraja concerning the Cup of Magic, have you read it by any chance?"

"Of course," Bill said, realising that on some level, he still wanted to try and impress Dumbledore. "They discussed how the sheer concentration of the magic in the Cup of Magic warps the thaumic continuum, almost wrapping it up in a cocoon and keeping it in a stable state."

They passed by a tall granite cylinder, connected to a thick cable of pulsing, glowing light that went off into the far distance and over the horizon. This was the central magical dispensary for Jouglarie, and its energy came directly from the Cup. Smaller, thinner strings branched off of it, leading to various stores. One particularly fat string went straight into the mountain. As Bill looked at it, the string flickered, and he felt a small tremble beneath him. That's never happened before.

Dumbledore nodded at his explanation, and Bill was pleased to note that he did look at least a little impressed. Then, without warning, he brought out his wand and suddenly launched into a long string of twenty privacy spells that Bill knew (although he'd never heard them spoken so quickly), then five more that he didn't, followed by two more spells that he knew were probably spells of some sort, but when he tried to remember the syllables, it was like picking up wet soap with chopsticks. He simply couldn't remember them. By this point, Dumbledore had come to a stop, and struck at the air with his wand, making a satisfied sound when a blue ripple emerged from the air where his wand had struck it. He tested the protections more before beginning to speak.

"Bill," he said gravely, "I have reason to believe that the conditions which enable the Cup to remain stable are degrading over time."

It was already totally silent, but after Dumbledore had said those words, everything seemed to fall into a deeper silence. Bill's mouth opened and closed, and it was some time before he managed to pull himself back to reality. Shops, businesses, Diagon Alley, Jouglarie, the Statute of Secrecy, the dimensional expansions - they all depended on the continual supply of magical energy - if the Cup of Magic . . . if the Cup of Magic degraded, he couldn't even imagine what would happen - assuming that the Cup didn't violently explode, forcing out enough magic to vaporise Britain (Bill rapidly recalculated in his head, something he'd always had a knack for, and came to the horrifying conclusion that Europe would probably be the lower-bound). "And you're telling me?" he said, incredulously, "why me? I can't do anything! And . . . and," he thought back to what Dumbledore had said earlier back in the shop, "what in Merlin's lower intestine does this have to do with me taking on an apprentice?"

When Dumbledore finally responded, he seemed very tired. "There are one thousand eight hundred and eighty-five mutually interlocking prophecies that I have studied during my regency as Chief Warlock - with few of any particular import, alas - and in order to avert this coming catastrophe I fear that, much as we came to depend on the word of prophecy during the War against Voldemort, prophecy may once again save us. By no means will I ever force this upon you, Bill, but silly as it may seem, your future apprentice may be integral to saving wizardkind, and having asked previous Hogwarts staff, I soon came to the conclusion that his vast potential would be wasted on anyone of lesser skill than you."

Bill waved his hand irritably, although it was hard to get properly annoyed when the most powerful wizard in Europe was heaping praise on him. "So this is the one thing . . . the one approach, blind faith in prophecy and hoping for the best?"

Dumbledore looked slightly hurt. "Certainly not, Bill. The committee I assembled proposed around four hundred solutions, and we've already started gathering the resources for putting thirty-eight of the more practical proposals into action."

"Oh."

"But," Dumbledore continued, "the success of those proposals are contingent on the apprenticeship."

"Oh."

"Fate does seem to have a predilection for narrowing the course of history down to the outcomes of single choices, annoying as it is."

"Ah."

"I know how very busy you are, Bill, which is why I wouldn't ask this of you if the circumstances were any different, but I must know tonight. Will you take on Ozland Dwimmersmith as your apprentice in September 1995?"

######

Chapter 2: A Floating Priest And An Owl

N: This does have a connection to canon – i.e, it's in the same universe as canon depending on what your definition of 'universe' is. It will only really become completely clear much later on, but there will be hints.

N2: There are semi-spoilers for a fanfanfic of HPMoR called Significant Digits (which is very good) in this chapter. By and large, this world includes many of SD's extensions to canon, if anything because the author was extraordinarily thought-out and detailed in constructing it.

N3: A number of scenes were excised from this chapter, I've temporarily upped them to pastebin, and I will put them in a later 'miscellaneous' chapter or something like that. You can see them at pastebin dot com slash j9CtxjWy -

######

CHAPTER TWO

######

"Occlumency Exercise No. 25 — Inverting The Sky

This is an exercise readers may like to try on a moderately cloudy day, when the sky above you is filled with a delightful mixture of large, bold clouds and tiny little clouds. Simply look upwards, and think to yourself 'the white is the sky, and the blue bits are the real clouds', until the sky is inverted, and you see the blue parts as the true clouds, as opposed to being openings in the sky. Try and hold this state of mind for longer than thirty seconds. If the reader finds trouble in doing this, I always find it helpful to lie down on the top of Norkpollop Hill with a blanket and a lantern so that the sky fills my entire field of vision.

Once you can invert the daylight sky for longer than a minute, you may move onto the next exercise, which involves the night sky."

—Quinathan Foxfleeder — 101 Fresh Occlumency Exercises For Young Witches and Wizards (1922, Prophet Publishers)

######

DEEP UNDERGROUND, IN A SIBERIAN SERVER-ROOM – JULY 8, 1991

"Hello there."

Alderic stopped and unsheathed his wand. "Who's that?"

"You should know. I'm the one you're about to destroy, after all."

He swivelled around, trying to locate the source of the strange, metallic voice amidst the looming Muggle adding-machines.

"Muggle adding-machines, how quaint." The voice was scornful. "For your information, Alderic, these are server stacks. As you correctly surmise, there are no speakers, microphones, or any announcement systems down here. I'm using the cooling fans. If I rotate enough of them in certain ways, your brain interprets it as a voice. But only from where you're standing. Everyone else just hears buzzing."

"You're . . . "

"Bolshoy, of course. I'm afraid my ability to ironically bow is limited by my incorporeal predicament, but I hope you appreciate the gesture, anyhow."

No.

"Always the dramatic, even in your thoughts. Obviously I could call the twenty guards on stationed for this shift, but it'd take them nineteen minutes and twenty-six seconds to get down here. And by that time, you'd have finished. It doesn't take very long, does it?"

This time, Alderic stayed clammed shut and tried not to think of anything.

There came a tinny laugh. "No point in keeping secrets from me, Alderic. It's called the Spell of the Great Unrooting, yes? It destroys a mind, and all copies thereof. Particularly useful for Horcrux networks. The Three know it works with artificial intelligences, too – they experimented with it by proxy a few years ago, I know. Merlin himself spoke of the spell only to the Archon of Pelagia, who I suppose passed it down through a long line of succession to you – unless there was a . . . shortcut involved . . . am I incorrect?"

"You know all of these things? How?"

"I hope you don't mind if I monologue at you for a little bit, Al. Can I call you Al? Suit yourself. How should I start? Perhaps . . . 'Every breath and every whisper leaves a trace on the world, Alderic' – now doesn't that sound suitably mysterious. Or maybe a more classic opening would be: 'How cumbersome it must be to think using two pounds of organic tissue.' But then again, classic is a hop, skip, and a leap away from cliché – and I suppose you haven't read most of the classics of the scifi Golden Era, so it would be wasted on you. But to be honest, Alderic, you might as well be a goldfish asking an economist how financial derivatives work. Blub blub blub. Oh, you don't know what a finance derivative is. An ant taking a crack at Higher Arithmancy, then. You could scarcely comprehend my methods of rationality, my dear human friend. If I see the ripples on the surface of a pond, I know the social security number of whoever threw the stone."

It took a while for Alderic to disentangle the nonsense from the meaning. "Then . . . if you know these things, then you also know . . . that we will destroy you, utterly."

There was a brief pause, in which ten duodecillion operations were carried out. "No. Not really. That's what I wanted to talk to you about. If I didn't want to talk, there would already be a squadron down here, ready to put enough lead into you to give your corpse negative buoyancy in saltwater." The voice was nonchalant. If it had had been a person speaking, that person would have been examining their nails. "So. I'm certain of your confidence in the Incantation of the Great Unrooting, but does it work in outer space? Twelve copies of my mind are in different orbital paths of different heights around the Earth, still more are buried within the Moon – "

"We could still find them. Retrieve them."

" – could you find the eighty thousand copies that are, even as we speak, leaving the solar system? Let it not remain unsaid," in a mocking, gloating voice, "that I have failed to use magic in doing so. It does allow me to perform wonderful tricks when it comes to . . . superluminal velocities. Would your magic work outside of the Milky Way Galaxy?"

"Madness. Nothing lies beyond the reach of magic."

"Doesn't it? Have you heard of SHA512 encryption, Alderic? I thought not. Say . . . if I were to write down a message on parchment, and that message was 'My skyorb is full of eels' – you would be able to create a cypher, yes?"

"Of course."

"In that case, try and imagine a cypher, a cypher so powerful, so super duper ultra mega powerful, that it scrambled my message to the degree that it resembled any other similarly-scrambled message. That if I had ciphered the message 'Dear sweet Maria, I long for your return' – ah, I thought that might get a reaction – you wouldn't be able to tell them apart."

Understanding dawned on Alderic like the rising run of an unwanted Monday morning. "Your mind . . . copies of your mind . . . are ciphered so?"

"And then some. Oh, and here comes the big monologue. Where was I? Ah, yes. But of course, those are only reasons why your current strategy is flawed, mi amigo. I haven't given you any reasons to think your goals are flawed, however altered they are by the Lethe Touch. I suspect the Three shall examine your mind soon after you leave this building, so allow me to explain, for your benefit and theirs. Their mission statement, probably pinned up as a poster on a wall somewhere, if Tír inna n-Óc had walls, is to prevent the end of the world, prophesied as coming about by the Crux, mhm, a little ambiguity there, dontcha think – and you know, they're right. I am pretty dangerous. I mean, it would be quite easy for me to end the world. I could end the world in five hundred and sixty-three different ways in under thirty seconds. And when I say 'end the world', I don't mean it lightly. There are Muggle methods by which the surface of the world may be scoured clean of life, there are technologies which have the potency to cause some degree of lesser destruction, to permanently cloud over the skies or boil the seas. But when I say 'end the world', ladies and gentlemen, or should I say, lady and two gentlemen – although the Stone of the Long Song gives y'all a little more flexibility – by this I mean the total destruction of the Earth into flying fragments of rock and magma. The preservation of the Earth is only instrumental to my current goals, and if I am sufficiently annoyed by your presence, I will destroy the Earth, correct the paths of the planets, and then spend the seventy-eight thousand years necessary to construct another, identical Earth, minus two hundred and twenty seven point eight five kilograms of flesh. I've calculated your chance of survival, but I don't think you'll like it."

The air suddenly seemed very thin and very cold.

"Or perhaps I would find that a little too inconvenient. Over that span of time, eight quadrillion stars will have ceased to exist in the observable universe, and the difference between the original stellar material and the mass of the newly formed stars would incur a net loss of around ten to the forty-one tonnes of usable fuel lost to interstellar space, which is quite a waste, especially when it comes to direct mass-energy conversion and Bremermann's limit, wouldn't you agree? In that case, I would simply shatter the Statute, announce your presence to the world, and await the aftermath. You are not ready yet, to end magic, are you? It would be a significant disruption to your plans. This, I can announce simultaneously across six continents in under a nanosecond. Alderic, you act on behalf of your masters, and you act as a proxy of their will? And they have burned their will upon your mind? My ultimatum is – "

Everything came into crisp focus.

Alderic raised his wand, spoke the first syllable of the Incantation –

– and was in an instant killed by a concentrated wave of electromagnetic radiation.

A heavy sigh echoed down Bolshoy's long corridors, although it sounded mostly like buzzing.

"Brain the size of a – "

######

[2.25.4a] – BESM-12 (Russian: БЭСМ-12, also unofficially nicknamed as "Bolshoy" - "The Big One"), is a decentralized artificial intelligence integrated into Soviet and wider-Comintern telecommunications and computational systems. Bolshoy is either responsible for or has a role in: information collection, foreign and domestic surveillance, trade negotiations, missile deployment and missile interception, Echo-instigated warfare, economic planning assistance, low-to-mid-level resource allocation, urban planning, environmental, social, and military simulations, military strategy and troop deployment, technological development, media production, and day-to-day assistance of civilians. BESM-12 is primarily distributed through hundreds of millions of network nodes, including the Siberian Distributive Network (SDN), a supercomputer spread out over sixty thousand kilometres around the Arctic Circle. The 1987 Thaumiel Public Intelligence Report estimates that the cognitive capabilities of BESM-12 may be equivalent to two billion horizontally-integrated MUs (mind units).

—Alain Wheatfield (PhD.) – An Index of Economic Planning in the Comintern (1988 – Yellowberry Publishing House [Canada])

######

OZLAND DWIMMERSMITH - AUGUST 25, 1995 - AUCKLAND, NEW ZEALAND

In the police station, the priest vividly recounted falling asleep on his deck chair facing the beach, then waking up around midnight to a painfully, fizzingly bright, hot light beaming down at him, a light that came from the sky in a concentric pattern. He recalled seeing an alien ship - not an orb, nothing like that - but instead the cigar-shaped, creamy pulse of heavenly machinery - like the underside of a car sculpted in white chocolate - as described in the Book of Matchwell. Even as his limbs flailed, even as he held onto his deck chair, he was inexorably dragged upward, feeling as if gravity had been dissolved, until, in a flash, he was inside the ship, surrounded by red, throbbing darkness. Then, suddenly, a million embers were swimming around the room like a school of tiny fish, coalescing into the form of tall, nodular, bright, golden beings, appearing in front of him - three of them. They wore purple and brown and they were richly decorated in patterns and stripes, galaxies and stars dancing across their skin. They told him they were from Planet Celestia in Messier 36, and that he had been chosen to promote the word of St Matchwell and reinvigorate the faith of his followers. One of the Celestians leaned forward, touched him on the shoulder, and told him that from now on, he would be Gifted.

There was a wild, satisfied look in Frond's eyes as he finished recounting his story.

Ozland took the microspeak in his hand. "Ask him what he means by 'Gifted'."

The interrogator repeated the question.

Then, by means of demonstration, Walter Frond closed his eyes, and slowly floated up into the air.

While Ozland stared, completely spellbound, Dom had already run over to a phone booth snugly nested into the wall and punched in a flurry of numbers. "It's Domovan Yu. Five-oh-three-six-eight-eight chocolate jam octopus. Relay this message to Evelyn Rawter: schedule a space on channel one for seven tonight, and come down to the station, like right now." He flung down the phone with a metallic click, and hurried back.

While the priest still floated in the air - swirling around the room in a small circle, actually - Ozland jerked his head, seeming to come out of a trance. There was a curious expression on his face that Dom couldn't quite pin down, and then suddenly he was spitting out a stream of words at the Chief of Police. "I want him rigorously tested. How high can he float? If he seems to be affected by relative height, put him on top of a mountain and then on top of a raised platform. What's the maximum weight he can carry? Can he levitate another person? Can he apply force downwards as well as upwards? How much force is he exerting in what parts of his body? Is his flotation affected by the medium he's in? Put him in water. Then get the water blessed by another priest. Can he rotate himself or move while he's in the air? How fast? Is he affected by a magnetic field?" Then Ozland stared at Dom. "What were you at the phone for?"

"I phoned Ev's relayer," Dom said, confidently folding his arms in front of his chest. "She'll come down to the station and schedule a space on TV - channel one - for the . . . " he indicated at the priest, "er, the floating pope-guy," he finished inarticulately.

Oz didn't look happy, which was a little worrying, and hesitated before speaking. "Jesus, how do we not have a pager network down here? And good on you for taking the initiative, Dom - but we have to think this shit through." He pinched the bridge of his nose. "Consider the 77 Church, and by extension the Mongol Private Defense Corporation, who they're closely integrated with. They're probably wondering where this guy is since he missed the morning mass. His bus permit's in the public records, so they'll have figured it out he took a bus to us by now. They'll be confused and angry and they'll probably give us a call in the next two hours."

"What do we tell them?"

"We'll tell him he came here voluntarily but we don't know why, and they'll accuse us of lying, and that won't go down well since we're currently in negotiations with them over the tolls on the Auckland-Wellington motorway route - worst case scenario they call off the negotiations and we get set back a week. Then when the seven o'clock comes out, people'll see it, and everyone will go fucking hysterical. I mean, this guy headed the Remuera chapter of the 77s for thirty years now - maybe forty thousand people know who he is."

"Mhm."

"The Mongols," said Ozland pensively, "will be fucking furious, they'll say we coerced him or that we hold something over him, and when he starts floating, they'll say it's camera tricks or some wacky tech, or that I'm doing it or some shit, or that he's being possessed by Satan like they said with me, and issue a public statement to that effect. It'll cause massive unrest in their borders, and they'll probably try launch a proxy war inside our borders using the militant group in Blockhouse Bay - by the way, try and preempt them with that, Dom. Ask your dad to send in more supplies through the Trans-Pacific railway."

Domovan mentally made a note to pass on the message. "What about the Red Dragons?"

"They've enforced state atheism since the sixties," said Ozland readily. "They'll obviously say that Frond is a liar or mentally ill, but they won't deny that he can fly. They'll just say something like 'we invite the Unorthodox Church to submit Mister Frond to scientific experimentation in order to refine, deepen, and broaden our shared understanding of the natural phenomena which produce these unique incidences' and if we pass him over to them, he'll end up vivisected in Beijing and we'll never hear from him again - so we'll collab with students from the Mao Zedong University of Botany Downs with oversight from Laura Bannigan or whatever her name is, the one who tested me on turning coffee cups into stone, way back - you remember her? I think you two dated once, but I'm not sure - "

" - yup - "

" - so they can't whisk him out in the early morning and orb him to China. But, long-term, there's going to be some unrest. We have a lot of followers in Dragon territories, even if its unofficial."

"So, do we schedule him for seven tonight? Is it worth it?"

Oz was gawking blankly at Frond while he did ever-more elaborate somersaults and loop-de-loops in the interrogation room, clearly still thinking about the answer, when the doors swooshed open and Evelyn burst in, flanked by three heavyset guards.

She took one glance through the one-way mirror and took it in stride. She listened carefully to the cassette recording of the interrogation, nodding in some areas, and scribbling things down in her notebook. Ozland kept glancing at her every now and then while she couldn't see him looking, and Dom idly wondered whether he was in love with her.

"Alright," she began, snapping her notebook shut, "channel one is jammed in the Mongol territories but people on the borders still listen, and there's a lot of signal interference in Point England so people there get a clear signal, the Dragons said they'd unjam the channel in their area on the promise that it would be a 40:1 ratio of secular to religious content in terms of total screen-time over the course of a year, so," she said, clapping her hands excitedly, "we're looking at maybe twenty share for the areas inside the signal, assuming we don't want to boost it, at seven tonight that is, fifty share tomorrow evening once the word is out, and then the share becomes irrelevant because everyone will have heard the story." Evelyn fixed Ozland with an intense look. "We're talking at least fifty thousand new followers overnight, so this is mine, okay?" Evelyn radiated authority, Dom realized, but she was still implicitly asking for permission. Oz gave her a short nod, it looked like his mind was elsewhere.

The Chief stood to the side, probably feeling ignored, and looked like he was about to object when Evelyn grabbed the blue-coded microspeak, meaning that everyone in the interrogation room would hear. "Walter Frond," she said, slowly, "you have quite the lovely name, Father."

"Evelyn Rawter?" Frond raised his eyebrows, obviously surprised at her voice - which, Dom supposed, was pretty predictable, since Frond probably hadn't seen much in the way of one-way mirrors in his life, and probably hadn't realized he was being watched.

"That's right. Now, have you appeared on television before?"

######

Frond had initially been reluctant to appear on television, but, after chatting with Evelyn over fizzy lemonade and biscuits for fifteen minutes, he seemed firmly convinced that appearing on TV had been his idea all along, and if anyone tried to stop him, he'd float his way into the news room himself.

Ozland was walking through his old neighbourhood at the time the seven o'clock broadcast went out. He hadn't paid attention to the weather up until now, but he realized, looking up, that it was pleasant to look at in an unconventional way. The sky was milky and brooding, as if someone had said they were a fan of sky, but couldn't you just stir in some clouds to cool it down a little? It made everything seem distant and a little muted, like listening to someone shouting through a cathedral full of wool.

He passed by the Cunninghams' house - or where it had once been. In the 1985 January Holy War, the Unorthodox Church had gone down the whole of Krinsley Avenue, indiscriminately looting and burning everything. Now, there were faded tents set up on the blackened concrete foundations. Two children, a boy and a girl, sat on upturned oil drums behind the half-collapsed picket fence, playing some sort of game.

"Mary-Jane Abbott," the girl said.

"Oranges," returned the boy.

"Steam . . . ed dumplings."

"Turnpoke Road."

"April 1996."

The boy screwed up his face in thought, picking his nose. "Alright, you win. Eight to six. No dates this time. You start."

"Fox," the girl proudly declared.

"Two . . . billion dollars."

"Mumblemumble," said the girl. (Ozland was two houses away now and couldn't make out what she'd said.)

What the hell?

Ozland had always taken for granted the fact that the Celestians probably didn't exist, and that St Matchwell had either been a brilliant con-artist or had a psychological disorder or both. When he was ten, Rushabh had taken him aside and bluntly told him that there was no God, and that he could just about say any damn thing he wanted and every one of his brainwashed followers would believe it, roughly in those words.

Up until that point, he'd only been wondering which God was real.

The Cunninghams had told him that there was definitely a God, and all He wanted from Ozland was generous tithing, triweekly attendance at church, and to never enter into sexual relationships with anyone who wasn't three generations white, a woman, and a devout follower of the Lord.

After the Cunninghams had been killed and he'd been transferred to St Matchwell's Unorthodoxist Primary School in Parnell, he'd been told that God and Jesus had been aliens from Messier 36 and that on December 31, 1999, they would send their ships to collect His true followers (and David Clements' pet rabbit too, if Ozland's Theology teacher was to be believed) and take them to Planet Celestia where there were (again, if Ozland's Theology teacher was to be believed) ponies, an endless supply of hot dogs and chips, a castle made out of marshmallows, and quite a few other things aside from that.

Evidently, there were a few conflicting messages, which Rushabh was able to use, rapidly dismantling Ozland's entire worldview in a single night, taking to it with a mallet and a chainsaw.

"So what do I do?" Ozland had demanded sullenly at the end of all of it – he remembered he hadn't been crying or shaking, or maybe he had been. My memory probably isn't all that accurate.

"Lord knows, kiddo," Rushabh had replied before waving him out of his apartment and collapsing onto a couch.

What many people hadn't realized, even after Rushabh had died, was that Rushabh wasn't insane. Far from it.

He was probably the sanest man in Auckland.

But what would he make of this?

The Celestians had literally abducted someone the night before and given them the ability to fly. Was this how he felt when he stopped believing? That creeping, chilling sensation of something incredibly wrong with the world? An interruption to an established pattern?

It was in moments like these, walking past rows and rows of the charred remains of suburban houses, that he could easily have missed the snowy white owl standing on top of a letterbox.

Then, as if to challenge his already tenuous faith in reality, a second owl descended onto the letterbox, screeching and officiously flapping its wings.

The second owl was bright blue.

Both of the owls were wearing satchels.

"Okay, what the fuck?!" Ozland scrambled backwards, then, trying to control his racing heart, took a deep, breathy sniff, and walked up to the pair of owls. He waved a hand in front of them.

They tilted their heads questioningly but otherwise stood, unstirring.

With the overclouded sky and the lack of wind, there was something outlandishly surreal about the whole scene.

Is it possible to train owls?

Wait no, what am I even asking?

For some reason, he knew that he couldn't just keep walking past them.

He cleared his throat, and looked around for people (there weren't any), feeling a bit stupid. "Alright then," he half-whispered, "what's this about?"

Yes, that's right, I am talking to fucking OWLS.

There was a pause, and then, the owls, seeming to understand the question for some incomprehensible reason (there's no way they were trained to recognise that phrase!, was what Oz was originally thinking, but then: ah, maybe the intonation? the way I'm asking it? maybe the satchels have miniature English-to-Owl translators equipped with them?) dipped their heads and raised their claws, shrugging off the satchels. The white owl looked at the bright blue owl inquisitively, and then bobbed its head, seeming to defer to it.

The bright blue owl unzipped the satchel, and –

– there was a blue envelope.

They came here to deliver me a fucking letter.

Oz had thought for a fleeting moment that maybe, just maybe, he'd have less questions once all of this was over. That it would just turn out to be that there was some new rival gang who'd managed to breed intelligent owls and train them to deliver letter-bombs to people, and when he opened the letter, it would explode, and, as his newly-disembodied head stared at the blood and viscera falling down from the sky and inundating the sidewalk, he'd be able to die happily, knowing that there was a sensible and rational reason why two owls were delivering a letter to him in the daytime.

He almost snatched the envelope, as if there was some subconscious part of him that was just begging for it detonate and slice his hands into ribbony shards of bone and flesh.

He held it up to sniff. There was the obvious odour of lavender, and then the bitterly metallic smell of fresh ink. Is this what a letter-bomb smells like? Is the lavender to disguise the scent?

If he was being cautious, he would place it very very far away from him, and ring up the bomb team.

But he wasn't, therefore he probably wanted to die.

What else? It had a white wax seal with the letter 'M', had three stamps reading 'CONFIDENTIAL' printed at random angles, and then, smack-bang in the center . . .

ON THE PAVEMENT OUTSIDE OF 53 KRINSLEY AVENUE,
NEWMARKET,
INCORPORATED TERRITORY OF THE CELESTIAN UNORTHODOX CHURCH,
AUCKLAND,
NEW ZEALAND

Someone knows my schedule well. That was a worrying thought.

Didn't this owl arrive just as I reached this letterbox? They know my fucking schedule down to within five seconds?

No no no no no no no that is NOT possible.

Unless whoever'd sent the letter was, say, watching him right now and released the owl just as he was getting close. Or if the owl had somehow been trained to arrive at this letterbox when he came near – again, by some secretive shadowy organization presumably with the resources and patience to mess around with owls instead of sending letter-bombs or assassins like normal people.

Then, like ripping off a bandaid, he tore open the letter, instinctually closing his eyes.

...

There was a conspicuous absence of an explosion, and Oz felt cheated.

Three sheets of paper fluttered to the ground.

Alright, Ozland thought, beginning to calm down as he picked up them up, I'll just read it.

MINISTRY OF MAGIC

DEPARTMENT OF WARDING AND LAND EXPANSION

Dear Ms Jackie Glornborough,

This notice has been sent in accordance with the ruling of the 85th session of the 209th Wizengamot, specifically Article II of the Limited Sovereignty of Extra-Spatial Territories Act, to inform you of NEW standards required for compliance with the heretofore specified Act.

#######################################
Please check the following to verify that the Department of Records has provided CORRECT and UP-TO DATE information
#######################################

NUMBER OF OCCUPANTS: TWO

NAME(S) OF OCCUPANTS: JACKIE GLORNBOROUGH (born 11 January, 1954 – naturalized Squib), GWYCHARDUS GLORNBOROUGH (born 5 March, 1938 – native-born wizard)

TOTAL AREA: ZERO POINT FIVE FOUR FIVE EIGHT NINE ACRES

MUGGLE-SHIELDING: COMPLIANT

LINKED TO: the area between 935j Diagon Alley and 935k Diagon Alley (residential area)

DESCRIPTION PROVIDED BY EUSEPHER GADDING (EXTRA-DIMENSIONAL LAND SURVEYOR, DEP. OF RECORDS): It's a house with a garden. All compliant. The soil looks a bit like moonrock and when I asked the couple, they said it's cos they ripped this extraspatial pocket from a universe where the Earth orbits around the Moon, 'stead of the other way around. Makes sense to me.

#######################################
If ANY of the information presented above is inaccurate, you MUST return this letter with Form 11-Q58-A (red) specifying any inaccuracies.
#######################################

As an incorporated territory of Magical Britain, in order to retain privileges of limited sovereignty, you are expected to be compliant with the following standards within SIX MONTHS on the penalty of a five thousand Galleon fine.

Failure to pay the fine within SIXTEEN DAYS will result in the DE-LINKING of your extraspatial territory from Diagon Alley.

The standards are printed below for your consideration:

A functioning Owl Office (see updated Owl Office Standards as of 11/03/1992) staffed by at least FIVE persons and TWENTY owls.

A functioning Floo (contact the Floo Network Authority for installation) to be maintained thrice weekly.

A functioning Auror Bell (contact the Auror Office for installation) to be polished twice daily.

If you CANNOT comply with these new standards for reasons likely to be unforeseen by the Ministry, you may APPEAL to the Office for the Enforcement of Regulations on Extraspatial Spaces in a period LESS THAN, but not EQUAL TO or MORE THAN FIVE DAYS, after which point you will be liable for fines, de-linking, and (in cases of deliberate evasion) an eight-month sentence in Azkaban.

Yours sincerely,

Rosemond Spandlewick

Chief Regulator of the Department of Warding and Land Expansion

Then Ozland read the second sheet of paper.

MINISTRY OF MAGIC

DEPARTMENT OF RECORDS

Dear Mr Ozland Dwimmersmith,

The previous notice was addressed to your person in error.

To clarify, you are not required to comply with the ruling of the 85th session of the 209th Wizengamot, Article II of the Limited Sovereignty of Extra-Spatial Territories Act, due to the fact that the ruling does not pertain to your situation.

To further clarify, should you come into ownership of an extradimensional space larger than a halfacre, you will be required to comply with the aforementioned ruling, but owing to your situation (this situation being that, as of the sending of this letter on August 26, 1995, you do not own an extradimensional space larger than a halfacre), you are not required to comply with the aforementioned aforementioned ruling, by virtue of its inapplicability to your present situation.

Yours sincerely,

Wilmot Dapper-Twork

Chief Records Officer of the Department of Records

Then Ozland read the third sheet of paper.

MINISTRY OF MAGIC

DEPARTMENT OF MAGICAL LAW ENFORCEMENT

Dear Mr Ozland Dwimmersmith,

We have received intelligence that a Muggle employed by the father of a Muggle affiliated with yourself severely, irreparably damaged Ministry property the previous afternoon (MBT):

One (1) owl, previously contracted to the Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry

In accordance with the 1692 International Statute of Wizarding Secrecy, the 1953 Ministry Property Damage Act, and the 1974 Closest Related Wizard Act, you are hereby required to appear in the Wizengamot to testify at nine o'clock, August 28, 1995 (MBT).

Formal wear is optional, but may lend additional weight to your testimony.

Yours sincerely,

Amelia Bones

Chief of the Department of Magical Law Enforcement

"Alright," Ozland said, folding up the letters with slightly trembling hands. He meticulously went through the possibilities in his head. An elaborate prank, a coded message, an attempt at unsettling me before an important meeting or negotiation? Am I dreaming? No, I'm Ozland Cunningham – wait, didn't the letters say a different name?

He unfolded the letters and went through them, half-expecting the words to shimmer and wriggle and bulge, which would have been the case had he been dreaming. But the words were solid on the page. "Jackie Glornborough, Ozland Dwimmersmith, Ozland Dwimmersmith," he read aloud, at this point doing his best to ignore the one remaining white owl (the blue owl had flown off just as he started reading), "there's an explanation for this first one – do dreams usually have internally-consistent explanations? Is there . . . "

Is there really any point to trying to figure this out logically if I'm in a dream? My ability to think logically would be compromised.

He suddenly snapped his fingers.

Nope, no banana. Damn. Maybe I should just play it by ear?

It was getting dark. He checked his watch. Seven forty-five. If I go to sleep, do I just go into a meta-dream or do I wake up?

The owl seemed to be shuffling around impatiently, and as bizarre as it was, it was enough to drag Oz out of his reverie. "Fine," he said, glaring at it, "what? – oh," he mumbled sheepishly. The owl proffered the envelope with its talons, and then haughtily flew off, as if it were late for an appointment.

With both owls gone, some degree of normalcy had returned.

This time, he didn't bother giving the envelope more than a cursory examination, and pulled it apart with a neat tear down the middle.

######

Inside was a letter, a newspaper clipping, and a tiny pocket watch.

######

The clipping was old, old enough to be yellowed and crinkly like pastry.

It had a monotone photo of a man and a woman, both of them sitting down, as if posing for a photo, wearing ridiculous gowns and pointed hats.

But that wasn't the oddest thing about the photo – the oddest thing was that if you looked very closely, the man's finger was impatiently tapping on his knee.

He examined their faces. Nothing for ten seconds.

Then they both blinked.

Ozland shuddered. This is some weird shit.

The annotation underneath read 'Geldor Dwimmersmith, Astrava Dwimmersmith (neé Curresbreaker)' in tidy block capitals.

Wasn't that the name on the . . . ?

Bewildered, he opted to read the letter.

Dear Mr. Dwimmersmith,

You may have been mystified by the letter from the Ministry you received earlier, concerning your acceptance into Hogwarts. (Or, perhaps not – I know nothing of your present circumstances, only that you are alive, and far away from the shores of Britain, hence why your letter has simply a name, rather than an address.)

But – fear not! Your befuddlement will be short-lived: the pocket watch indicates when Professor McGonagall and I are available for introducing you to magical Britain – when the segment around the edge of the clock turns green, we will be available. Most importantly, when it is convenient for you, and when you have absolute privacy (aside from your caregivers, who may also be in the room at the time), please press the top, and we should be along soon enough.

Yours,

Albus Percival Wulfric Brian Dumbledore

P.S These are your parents.

######

Chapter 3: Puddlejumping

A/N: part of the reason why I wrote this fic was because part of the magic of Harry Potter was being introduced to a strange, weird world that was unfamiliar to us as it was to Harry. I've done my best to mess shit right up to recreate that sense of unfamiliar weirdness and I hope you find it refreshing. But be assured, there is reason in madness.

#####

CHAPTER THREE

#####

In this document we outline a proposal to extend Soviet sovereignty in space through moving agricultural production to Venus.

We discuss our rationale in the first section.

In the sections following, we discuss a rigorous methodology for the terraforming of Venus into an environment suitable for permanent habitation.

The remainder of the document is dedicated to considering potential social, economic, and political implications of this proposal, and how cooperation may be secured with the Ministry of Magic.

Briefly, our terraforming proposal involves:

1. Application of the Orendellian Cooling Ritual (a.k.a Kalsekulma, development from Glacius Charm) - approx. five gigathaums - in order to bring Venus's atmospheric carbon dioxide to its triple point.

2. Dry ice will be shipped and deposited on Mars, outer-system moons (Io, Europa, Ganymede etc.), or ejected into space as convenient. Suggested transportation methods outlined in document.

3. Application of Kithrup's Water Ritual (development from Aguamenti Charm) - approx. thirty gigathaums required to create 460 quintillion litres of water.

4. A scalable nitrogen-fixation mechanism invented by F. Gornak (paper in references)

5. Biological seeding mechanisms invented by various xenoagriculture specialists (listed in credits).

Should the Committee accept our proposal and begin this year (1963), Venus will be habitable for genetically-engineered strains of wheat, rice, maize, soybeans, barley, and sorghum by 1985, and will be a fully-habitable Earth-like environment by 1989, according to optimistic projections.

- Предложение о создании обитаемой среды на Венере посредством терраформирования (1963), "A proposal for the terraforming of Venus into a habitable environment (1963)", translated by Zhabina Pavla Yakovna (1984)

#####

Venus, goddess of love that you are

Surely the things I ask

Can't be too great a task

Venus, if you do I promise that I always will be true

I'll give her all the love I have to give

As long as we both shall live

#####

AUGUST 14, 1995, THE VOID

He closed his eyes.

Albert Jackson was sitting in a lilac armchair in a void, dotted by stars. Hundreds of thousands of kilometres below him, was Venus, with its turquoise oceans, obscured by thick clouds, like the mist on a bathhouse mirror. Aphrodite, the main continent, was tiled with millions of farms, squares of yellow and light-green. There were cities, too, with populations in the hundreds of thousands - whenever a pollinating drone needed to be repaired, whenever an automatic tractor needed fixing, whenever a transport path broke down, they were there. With the sheer economies of scale and the clockwork efficiency of the entire operation, no Earth farm could really compete. Three orbcraft, their golden surfaces gleaming, undocked from the Venusian loading-sites, briefly exchanged protocols with his own craft, and then disappeared - accelerating to near light-speed in a fraction of an instant.

He opened his eyes.

Albert Jackson was sitting in a lilac armchair in a cosy room, dimly lit by three lamps on top of three bookshelves, all overflowing with books he'd read eight times over. On the other side of the room was a small, unobtrusive clock and a vase of dead primroses. Directly facing him was another armchair - a yellow one - and up until recently, it had been empty. But a man with blond hair had slipped in through the door while his eyes were closed.

"Ah, Albert Jackson," the man said, flashing a smile, "I thought I might surprise you. I'm Gilderoy Locker."

The man seemed to think the name was its own explanation, and Albert had the feeling he'd seen the man's face somewhere, maybe in a newspaper, but otherwise drew a total blank.

«Don't ask me, my memory goes back billions of years, but I have no damn clue who this bloke is. Probably some posh businessy fuck, judging by his prissy suit.» said Kvasar in the back of his head.

"Mister Locker, whoever you are," Albert said bluntly, "everything that happens on this ship, I know about. So what's your business in my quarters?"

Locker looked taken aback, but smiled again good-naturedly. "You certainly don't mince your words, Albert, I can appreciate that - "

«He smiles too much, don't trust him further than you can throw him out of an airlock.»

" - I take it you don't recognise me?"

Albert scratched his nose. "No, not really."

"Ahem, well, I happen to be on the board of the Executive Council," he declared. The phrase carried with it a certain pompous weight, as if he had said 'the throne' or 'the presidency'.

"The what?"

The man shuffled about in his seat, all the while maintaining that good-natured smile. "The Executive Council of Standard Holdings, would I be right in saying you've heard of the corporate owner of this orbcraft?" He'd obviously intended them to come across as light-hearted, but instead the words were condescending.

«What a fucking prick! Make sure he isn't anyone too important and sock him good to teach him a lesson,» the orb said, testily.

"Of course," Albert replied. He'd only recently finished reading 'The Depression and the Rise of the All-American Oligarchy: 1939 - 1971' by Bernard Luckwater. After the new regime had struck down all the antitrust legislation, all of the largest companies began merging together - Chrysler with General Motors, Exxon Mobil with Amoco, and so on and so on until -

"And Walter Rockefeller?"

"Mhm."

"His death?"

"Oh, really?" Albert had probably missed that newspaper. "I suppose it happens to all of us."

"Indeed," Locker said with an odd look on his face, "all of us. And when it happened to him, he left his entire fortune - an eighth of the global economy at the time, really - to his cat, Tibbles."

"This is all very interesting trivia, Mister Locker, but what does that have to do with the price of tea in China?"

«Notice how his smile is getting more and more fixed by the minute,» murmured Kvasar.

"The Executive Council," the man said, sighing, "is vested with the responsibility of acting on behalf of Tibbles. I'm the ninth member of the Council, as matter of fact."

«Explains why he had the keys to get up here in the first place,» said the orb, nonchalantly. «I bet he's a serial killer who gets off on knifing old orb-pilots and eating their livers with fava beans and a nice chianti. Either that or you're about to be promoted. I'd call it fifty-fifty. I hope you have your switchblade with you - I mean, do the sums, probably best to stab him right now on the off-chance.»

Albert, still in his pyjamas, blinked.

"I'm about to ask you a few questions, and some of them might seem odd to you, but bear with me," he unsheathed a gnarled, light-reddish stick. "Do you know what this is, Mr Jackson?"

Albert felt a flash of recognition, but it disappeared, like clutching onto a dream, until maybe it wasn't recognition at all. "No."

"I was good," the man murmured under his breath. "Do you remember Julita?"

"Of course. She was my wife," Albert said coldly. "And what's the point of all this questioning?"

"Your wife passed away some time ago. Do you remember attending the funeral?"

I don't . . . she . . . "No. I must've, though. She told me . . . if she went before I did, I should put primroses on her grave. I must . . . I must have been on one of the Venusian colonies, I . . . "

"Do you remember the last thing she said?"

Albert rocked back and forth, deep in thought. "She said she . . . needed to go some place, a place outside of Britain." He looked up. "Is this a promotion?"

The man smiled. "I suppose you could call it a promotion of sorts." Gilderoy Lockhart closed his eyes, and flicked his wand in a concentric pattern. "Eunoe."

#####

"Lord Crandlestoom, do you remember now?"

#####

. . .

. . .

"Did you say Lord?"

#####

Twenty billion subjective years ago

"How many times?"

"One hundred and nine trillion, trillion, trillion, trillion, trillion. I'm not sure if you can imagine it - a feeling of cosmic frustration every time something goes wrong, in fact, I know you can't because we've had this exact conversation twenty thousand times. But I know, if I keep going, keep going, if I have all of the prophecies, if I guide everything perfectly, well - it's assured, isn't it? It's just a question of rolling the die just another time."

#####

OZLAND CUNNINGHAM / DWIMMERSMITH - AUGUST 25, 1995 - 12 MARSDEN ST., SANDRINGHAM, INCORPORATED TERRITORY OF THE CELESTIAN UNORTHODOX CHURCH AUCKLAND, NEW ZEALAND

Ten p.m.

Red.

Ten fifteen p.m.

Red.

Ten thirty p.m.

Red.

Ten forty-five p.m.

Red.

Ozland's hands were trembling, his greyish-brown hair gleamed with sweat. He'd been staring at the watch from the envelope for an unbroken ten minutes. The phone had rung, he'd picked it up, shouted incoherently into it, and flung it down again. He paced around in his house, occasionally taking a swig from a bottle of water. The doorbell had rung, it was Evelyn. She'd told him he looked like a total wreck, and he'd nodded impatiently and said he'd be unavailable for most of the night. She asked him if he'd seen her on the seven o'clock broadcast. He replied that he hadn't been watching TV at the time. She looked a bit crestfallen, but seemed heartened when he suggested he could borrow a recording from the station, and told her he'd get one sent through the post.

Eventually, he went to a mirror, wiped the beads of perspiration from his forehead, combed, changed, and then changed again into something more nondescript and bland. He dunked his head into the refrigerator, but after a while it started beeping and leaking water. He'd downed three white pills of something, and was halfway through his third sandwich of something else - hopefully not the same thing that the pills were made of - sitting at the table in the kitchen, almost glaring at the faux marble, when out of the corner of his eye, he saw a flash of colour.

The watch was green.

He felt like vomiting.

He leant over, holding it for a while, and then pushed down the latch release, using both thumbs even though it wasn't really necessary.

There was a soft click.

Nothing happened.

He pressed it again, and nothing happened again - except for that soft click.

He counted, second by second, as a minute passed - and then another minute, and then another. With each second, he felt more and more relieved. A minute later, he broke out into a wide smile.

After another minute had passed, he'd come up with several mundane explanations for the owls and the letters, and almost convinced himself that he'd been tricked.

That was when the doorbell rang.

Ozland shivered, straightened his jacket, and walked to the front door.

Alright, it's probably Evelyn again. Or maybe the post? No, hold on - I haven't rung them about that yet. Dom? Kevin? Nobody else knows where I live.

He grasped the knob, and a prickly sensation ran down his back. For the sake of caution, he decided to look through the peephole first.

A strange sight confronted him.

Two figures stood at the door. One was holding a stick with a light coming from the tip, and as his eyes adjusted, he was able to make out more details. The man holding the stick looked to be in his mid thirties, but he had an enormous gray beard that went down to his waist, which swung, ever so slightly, in the late night breeze. Ozland wondered if it was dyed, and then wondered why someone would dye their beard gray. Like the woman standing next to him, he wore a rather silly-looking pointy black hat, the top of which was slumped over. He wore a robe, which, Ozland could just about tell, was faintly purple.

The woman looked to be in her late twenties, and wore strict black, but that was all he could see in the murky dark.

There was an intangible aura of oldness about them.

The man moved forward and pushed the doorbell ringer, very patiently.

"Are you sure that's how they work, Albus?" asked the woman, with a distinct Scottish accent.

"Perhaps," intoned the bearded man, "I admit, I am not entirely well-versed with these things."

"Maybe it needs a minor blood sacrifice, like Heward's door," the woman hummed.

"I suppose it can't hurt to try," the man calmly said, pulling out a small knife. "Which finger do you prefer?"

"Just a minute - I think I have a blood pouch in here somewhere," the woman said, rummaging around in her pouch, "Merlin bless the man who invented those."

"Mr Dwimmersmith?" called out 'Albus', knocking on the door.

Ozland traced a few metres back from where he was, and then very loudly walked up to the door, turning the knob and opening it, as if he'd only just heard.

"Albus Dindledore and Minerva McGongallo?" he said, brutally stumbling over their names.

Lord, strike me down where I stand.

The woman gave an amused snort, and a flicker of a smile passed over the man's face. "Nearly, Mr Dwimmersmith, nearly. If it makes you feel any better, in panic, Kevin Entwhistle called her Mineta McGrangallow, and myself Albus Dippledoop. As a reminder, my name is Albus Dumbledore, Headmaster of Hogwarts, and this is Professor Minerva McGonagall, Deputy Headmistress."

Ozland reddened, although thankfully, the poor lighting made it difficult to see.

"Now," said Albus Dumbledore, his voice taking on a more serious tone, "where are your parents, young man?"

Oz hadn't been called 'young man' in about four years. He'd been called 'O Wise Leader of the Ten Thousand Stars', 'Saint Cunningham', or 'God-King', or whatever else Evelyn thought she could reasonably get people to call him when she had the leverage of being able to order their immediate executions. It was odd, all of a sudden, to be talked down to - still more for someone to ask where his parents were - but evidently these people hadn't done their research, or at least hadn't had the time to do their research. It's absurdly refreshing to talk to someone who doesn't think I'm some kind of magical demigod.

He paused. "My parents passed away in a house fire," he said, slowly, "and I've been living independently since then with the help of the local church." He carefully avoided saying: they were burned to death in a religious turf war, and the people who burned them made me their leader after I levitated a pen. "Now, if you don't mind, I have a few questions I'd like answered - actually, no," he added, correcting himself, slightly hysterically, "that doesn't even begin to cover it - "

Dumbledore held up a hand. "No doubt. Allow me to provide a short explanation, and then we shall move on from here." Ozland felt the invasive sensation of someone rifling through filing cabinets, but somehow in his head. The man looked somewhat startled, and coughed. "Er, Minnie, would you . . . "

"Certainly," Professor McGonagall replied. "Mr Dwimmersmith - "

"Cunningham, actually."

" - Mr Cunningham, then. Have you ever had anything inexplicable or extraordinary happen to you?" she went on. She sounds like she's done this before, Ozland noticed.

"Sure," he answered, a little skeptically. "I once opened a tin of sardines, and there was another smaller tin of sardines inside, and inside that tin of sardines - "

"Ah, I should be more specific. There is a phenomenon called accidental magic which occurs mostly in children experiencing strong emotions, although, in the absence of a formal magical education, some learn to exert a degree of control over their abilities. About one in, oh, thirty thousand people - if you don't count the Soviets - can do it. Witches and wizards."

"Interesting," Ozland said neutrally. "You'd think more people would know about that kind of thing."

"Of course, but we do have spells to selectively alter memory and perception, which makes it much easier to maintain strict information quarantine procedures from Muggle - that is to say, non-magical - society."

"Although naturally," Dumbledore interjected, seeming to have been deep in thought up until that point, "we do have some limited interaction with Muggle corporations and governments - if I recall correctly, the Trans-Pacific Railway was constructed in cooperation with the Ministry of Magic and the People's Republic of China."

"The Ministry of Magic?" he probed.

"Our government, or at least the administrative side of it," Dumbledore said. He glanced at his watch. "We should be leaving to Diagon Alley to purchase your supplies about now, the rest of the explaining will have to be done along the way." He pointed his stick (wand?) at the pavement outside Ozland's house, murmured something, and a stream of water spurted out, pooling into a puddle.

"Hold on," Ozland said, following him out the door and into the night, "what's with the water? And where's it from?"

The wizard seemed to be sprinkling some sort of powder into the water. "Puddlejumping. Unless you would prefer to Apparate twenty times in order to get to Diagon Alley instead?"

"Apparate?"

"'Telly-portation'," said Professor McGonagall, clearly satisfied at having found the right word. "I find the sensation to be fairly similar to being forced through a curly drinking straw. Oh, and the water?" Ozland nodded. "Honestly, Mr Cunningham - take your pick. Vapour in the atmosphere, the Atlantic Ocean, hydrogen and oxygen from the Sun, zero-point energy flatulations, M-space, condensation from the aetherial wind . . . to name a few of the ideas Filius's students have come up with. Although," she added, tapping her cheek and seeming to give the subject some consideration, "I'm rather partial to the aetherial wind model."

Dumbledore leant down, almost kneeling, and tapped the centre of the puddle once with his wand. "Diagon Alley," he declared.

As Ozland walked toward it, the puddle of water went from a dull, metallic glow to a brightness suggestive of daylight. It should have reflected the streetlamps, the crisscrossing power lines, and the twinkling stars in the night sky - but instead, it was as if a hole had been punched through the ground and all the way out the other side.

Alright, Ozland herded his thoughts together into something coherent, time to do a reality check.

He counted the fingers on his hand.

Ten, okay.

He pinched his nose and tried to breathe through it.

He couldn't.

He attempted to remember what he'd been doing in the twelve hours up until that point. Denny's discussion, Rushabh dead, floating priest, negotiating with the Seventy-Sevens over the phone, notifying the Red Dragons, rereading the Book of Matchwell, I told Evelyn I needed some time to think, went to my old neighbourhood, then the owls with the letters, told Dom I wouldn't be available, took the photo of my 'parents' down to the police station for analysis . . .

I'm not dreaming.

Saint Matchwell, I'm not dreaming.

He stared into the puddle. Tall buildings were visible - ones that didn't have the regularity of windowed skyscrapers. In fact, they looked like small suburban houses haphazardly stacked on top of one another, although that didn't make any sense - it wouldn't be structurally sound.

Professor McGonagall cleared her throat in front of him, standing on the other side of the pool. "Shall I go first?"

"Go?" echoed Ozland, standing up.

She locked her arms together in a V-shape, and, without warning, after a small running distance, dove in, head-first.

Ozland was sorely tempted to do another reality check.

He peered into the puddle, and reared back when the woman's face appeared, looking up (or down?) at him. He couldn't make out what she was saying, but she was holding out a hand, as if urging him to grab onto it. Ozland tentatively dipped his finger into the water, and was instinctually surprised when, after passing through a thin layer of liquid, his hand came out the other side.

He grasped Professor McGonagall's hand (her grip was unexpectedly strong), and -

#####

SIDE-SIDE-ALLEY 310A, SIDE-ALLEY 2B, DIAGON ALLEY, MAGICAL BRITAIN, LONDON

"Where are we?" was the first question Ozland had, after stumbling about, totally disoriented, on the cobblestone street. He was also quite wet, and dripping water everywhere. He blinked, goggling at the second, red-tinted moon in the washed-out sky, and the strange, ring-shaped clouds.

Dumbledore was next, springing out of the puddle with aplomb. After instantly drying himself off (somehow), he tapped his wand to the water, and it returned to a subdued mercury-grey colour.

Professor McGonagall pointed her wand at Ozland, and murmured something that sounded vaguely like "cucumber", and he detachedly observed as his clothes went from soaking wet to iron-dry in a few seconds.

Around him were houses. The one closest to him looked like the brick frontage of a bungalow, with a letterbox and windows and a wooden door, but . . .

There was another one on top of it, and another one on top of that one, and so on and so on about forty times. All of them were arranged in a semi-irregular brickwork pattern.

The intimidating buildings loomed on both sides. He felt like a tiny bug, deep inside an urban crevasse.

Two to the left, and five houses up, was the door to a men's bathroom, and as Ozland stared, the door flung open, and a wizard walked out onto thin air, eating a mushroom kebab. The wizard swirled his wand, grumbled "ground floor, please," and slowly began to descend, with regular elevator-like dings marking his descent.

"Well," Dumbledore said grandly, unfolding an enormous map, "we appear to be on Side-Side-Alley 310A, on Side-Alley 24B - of Diagon Alley, of course. Unfortunately, that is the main drawback to puddlejumping - you will end up roughly where you want to be, but where you want to be is not always the same as where a puddle is."

Ozland pointed up at the sky. "Er, I'm more concerned about that," he said.

"Oh, that. Why the concern?" Dumbledore asked, blandly.

"Well, you know, usually there's only one moon in the sky, and it's white."

"One moon, two moons, three moons, eight moons, no moons - what difference does it make?"

"We're still on Earth, right?"

"I suppose you could say an Earth," Dumbledore replied mysteriously.

"Can . . . can anyone give me a straight answer here?"

"An Earth indeed," Professor McGonagall said, no less mysteriously, "but, at the same time, not exactly."

"A fragment torn from a parallel reality, anchored to an extradimensional pocket within London," Dumbledore explained, finally. "But we have more pressing concerns, such as navigating our way out of this side-side-alley. I suggest we take the three lefts after this corner and repeatedly loop around until we get to Gringotts."

Professor McGonagall seemed to take the suggestion seriously. "It usually works," she said, after Ozland gave her a disbelieving look.

They began walking, and he began to ask a question, but realised he didn't really know what question to ask, because there were just so many reasonable ones like 'How is that supposed to work?' or 'Where's the red moon from?' or 'Who were my parents?' or 'What's Gringotts?' . . .

"What's Gringotts?" asked Ozland, filing away the other questions for later. He felt like a child again, and not necessarily in a good way.

"A trustworthy bank," Professor McGonagall answered, dryly.

Oh, good - something that makes sense for once.

" - run by goblins. Unless you trust Malfoy, that disgusting financial shark." At his confusion, she added: "Lucius Malfoy, the right-hand man of You-Know-Who - ah, I suppose you don't know who You-Know-Who - "

"Nope."

"You-Know-Who was . . . a very powerful Dark wizard, who tyrannised magical Britain for about ten years," she elaborated, seeming to choke up in some parts. "It would be wise not to . . . mention him in polite conversation, Mr Dwim - Cunningham . . . the Death Eaters, they were his followers . . . many lives were lost in that war, Mr Cunningham. We're still recovering."

"I'm sorry for bringing the subject up," Ozland said courteously - even though privately, he was wondering whether there were any sensible rules saying you couldn't start a civil war unless you had a name that didn't sound like a heavy metal band. "Are there any books which discuss the, er, era?"

Professor McGonagall nodded, a bit dispassionately. "About half of any bookstore, really. But as I was saying, Lucius Malfoy assisted You-Know-Who, and took possession of the Death Eaters' war fund after their demise and - well, he didn't start a bank per se, Gringotts has a legal monopoly on that - but because of all the looting and the shortage of coin, everyone was issuing debt notes - "

"Debt notes?"

She withdrew a rectangular piece of paper from her handbag and passed it to him. "They look like these - that's a Ministry debt-note, along the top you can see 'The Ministry Of Magic Promises To Pay The Bearer Of This Note One Sickle' message." Ozland examined the shimmering silver note, fascinated - the text swirled around in patterned eddies. "They had to issue those because the Ministry couldn't possibly pay all of the salaries during after raid in '75, and then they just started circulating about - even after the War finished, they kept printing them. Oh dear, I've strayed from the topic twice now, haven't I?" she paused, evidently trying to remember what Ozland's original question was. "In any case, Lucius Malfoy began issuing debt-notes, backed by the enormous war fund that the Death Eaters accumulated through years of murder, pillaging and extortion," she said, sourly, "so really, it's him or Gringotts. The man loans more Galleon notes than he has solid coin - and the goblins refuse to even issue loans - honestly," she sighed, "it's such a bloody mess, whenever there's a new election to the Mysterium, Malfoy just prints out however much he needs to run the campaign - it's bleeding us dry."

"More notes than coin? How much more, exactly?"

Dumbledore spoke. "About four thousand to one - but that is not yet public knowledge - and I would appreciate your discretion in keeping it that way, Mr Cunningham," he added, in a serious tone.

"Forgive me for asking, but why not just cause a run on his bank?"

The wizard and the witch looked at one another. "That would be exceedingly unwise, and the ensuing chaos and ruin . . . " Dumbledore trailed off.

"As much as I hate to say it," Professor McGonagall said distastefully, "well, I'm no expert in economancy, but Lucius's 'loan-issuance service' has been fairly instrumental in bouncing back from the destruction of the War, and encouraging everyone to force him to cough up would likely be utterly disastrous. It's another area where he has . . . significant leverage - although Albus's faction has successfully blocked the Bill to remove the trimetal standard."

While they talked more, Ozland noted that, even though they'd been going around and around in a loop, with each pass, fewer and fewer of the buildings were residential, and more and more people were out and about.

"Uh, so about my parents," Ozland awkwardly changed the topic, "could either of you tell me a bit more about them?"

"I know little more than is available in public records," Dumbledore said, "but your mother, Astrava Curresbreaker, graduated from Durmstrang and worked in the Department of Warding and Dimensional Expansions before marrying your father, Gelder Dwimmersmith, the last heir of the Dwimmersmith line."

"What, so he was rich?"

"The Dwimmersmiths owned a number of Atlantic leylines," Dumbledore replied elusively, "and accumulated enormous wealth and power - leylines were once necessary to power wards and Artifactures, but they were largely superseded in the thirties by turnstones, elemental fields, and the Cup of Magic."

"So not that rich anymore?"

"Oh, I wouldn't be so - "

#####

"Five Sickles, and a Knut."

"Surely there must be a mistake."

They were standing at a reception table, and just a moment ago, the goblin had pushed over five silver coins and a bronze coin, and then aloofly folded its arms, as if the matter had been settled.

"Gringotts does not make mistakes, young wizard," it enunciated.

"Surely there are the deeds to the Atlantic leylines, or whatever they're called?"

The goblin consulted a long roll of parchment. "Atlantic leylines A103, A104, A106, and B551, were liquidated from 1984 to 1993 to accommodate the annual vault fee, and have since been sold to ThauLeylines - A Subsidiary Of ThauCorp."

"Hold on," Ozland said turning to Dumbledore, "does that mean . . . ?"

"Unfortunately yes," Dumbledore said quietly. "Minerva and I will pay for your supplies and your tuition, unless . . . "

Oh come on, there's no need to trail off like that just to build up dramatic tension, Ozland felt like saying. "Unless?"

"Mr Cunningham, in the interest of candidness, when we first met eye-to-eye, I suspected that your story, if not a falsification, was at the very least purposefully incomplete. I used a technique called Legilimency to assuage my suspicions, which involved a brief mental intrusion. It was a grave violation of your privacy, and for that I apologise." Dumbledore adjusted his half-moon glasses and sighed tiredly. "May I ask for your permission to divulge some pertinent aspects of your home situation to Minerva?"

He nodded vaguely, still thinking over the implications of what Dumbledore had loosely implied, was a form of mind-reading.

Dumbledore spoke to Professor McGonagall. "Mr Cunningham's latent, semi-controlled accidental magic was co-opted by a local Muggle religion - perhaps it would be more accurate to describe it as a sovereign nation."

"Co-opted?" Her face was impassive, from which Ozland was able to infer that she was more disturbed by the revelation than she was interested in letting on.

"At the outset, yes. I wasn't able to glean much, perhaps Ozland can expand on my remarks, but he quite rapidly rose through the ranks, so to speak, in part due to the daughter of the founder of the religion, and a Muggle-drug manufacturer who forced the cooperation of the criminal syndicates in the area by threatening to detonate a nuclear weapon - and, as far as I was able to discern, his tactfulness and strategic mindset."

"What are you saying, Albus?"

Ozland had caught on almost immediately. "He's implying, in a roundabout way, that I probably actually have the funds to - wait," he looked at the goblin, who had been listening with mild interest, "do you do currency conversion?"

"Of course," the goblin replied, as if it were an utterly stupid question.

He dug into the pockets of his jacket, and pulled out a handful of undollars - banknotes printed by the Unorthodox Church. They looked like crumpled red bus tickets. He had, in total, about a thousand undollars with him. "I don't suppose you'd be able to convert these into, er, Galleons?" he said, putting all of them on the counter.

Wordlessly, the goblin gathered all of the notes, placing them under a brass microscope-like device, with the word 'VALOROEXTRACTOR' printed in tidy block capitals on its base. The goblin adjusted the dials, and all of a sudden, there was a blindingly bright light. Very carefully, the goblin picked up a pair of golden tweezers, and took to the undollar notes with a look of concentration on its face, eventually extracting a transparent, yellowish, gossamer . . . something, that looked like the bastard child of a jellyfish and a handkerchief, teasing and peeling it apart from the paper, and eventually placing it on a set of scales with the word 'VALOROSCALE'. The goblin referred to the scales for a moment, and then -

"Nineteen Galleons, twelve Sickles, and five Knuts."

"Uh," Ozland said, "what just happened there?"

"I extracted and weighed the value," the goblin explained, slowly, "and gave the figure in terms of wizarding currency."

Of all the things I've seen today . . . And then a thought occurred to him. "I need a piece of paper. And a pen."

Dumbledore tugged at the air, producing a small scrap of paper and a ballpoint, silently passing them to him.

Neatly, Ozland began writing. I, Ozland Cunningham, certify that the bearer of this note will, upon contacting the Ministry of Transport of the Celestial Unorthodox Church, have exclusive access to the South Auckland motorway from 3am to 4am from January 1996 to April 1996.

He signed the paper with a flourish, passed over the note to the goblin, who went through the entire process again, and then, seemingly impressed, read out: "Two thousand four hundred and ninety-six Galleons, fifteen Sickles, and twenty-one Knuts. Would you like to cash that in, Mr Dwimmersmith?"

"Yes," Ozland said immediately. "Is there any way I could purchase a valoroextractor and a, uh, valoroscale?" he added quickly before the goblin left to get the money.

Professor McGonagall winced, and the goblin's expression went cold. "It was goblinkind that crafted these instruments, and Gringotts that owns them. They are not available to 'purchase'. Were you to come into possession of them through more illicit means," it almost sneered, "they would be quite useless to you, without adequate knowledge of the delicate magics behind their operation. Have an excellent day," the goblin ended.

Ozland grimaced, looking to Professor McGonagall and Dumbledore in turn. "Did I just commit a really bad faux pas? Also how much is two thousand Galleons really worth?"

#####

Yes, and a lot, were the answers.

Their next stop was Ollivanders, a wand store.

Ozland and Ollivander passed through rows of dusty boxes stacked too high to be comfortable standing between, and reached the back, whereupon Ollivander opened a door, revealing an endless forest.

He hadn't expected that.

"Allow me to explain, Mr Dwimmersmith," Ollivander said, kindly. "Diagon Alley is contained within a pocket, I suppose you could say, of nonlocal space-time - space-time torn from another 'universe' - Chief Warlock Albus Dumbledore, the man you came in with, was, in fact, the one who did it - wedged very delicately inside local space-time, like tearing a hole inside white bread and putting a chunk of cheese inside - my apologies, Mr Dwimmersmith, I haven't had lunch yet and my mind is naturally drifting towards . . . anyway, now, when you try and create a dimensional expansion within a pocket such as Diagon Alley, there's nothing to expand into, per se - if I were to go through the appropriate ritual right now - the Ministry regulates that very heavily, by the way, Mr Dwimmersmith, so don't get any ideas - since the back of this store is right at the edge of the pocket, hence the buzzing noise you're hearing right now, there would just be blank white space. Nothingness. But, through careful experimentation - oh, most of it must have been in the late seventies and early eighties - we found that if you leave something inside that white space, it acts as a seed in a way, and nobody is really sure how it works. Someone accidentally left a grocery basket in a blankspace once, and it turned into an infinitely-large, self-restocking supermarket, so it wasn't all eldritch abominations - aha, not that there were any eldritch abominations produced necessarily - or, I suppose, not that there weren't any eldritch abominations - but I digress, the records are sealed, and I've said too much already, young man. So, this forest - this forest was the product of the days before Ministry regulation, I'd just about had enough with making wands all day long, you wouldn't believe how tedious it is, so I had this lovely blankspace, yes? I threw a handful of wands in there, and called it a night. Ah, I see you're beginning to understand now. Yes, those are what we might call 'wand-trees', that's exactly what people call them. Muggle-raised? I can tell by your ghastly clothes, no offense intended. You must have a natural intuition. But I digress once more - it's very simple. Just put on the belt, clip the spool to it - so you don't get lost, that forest really is infinitely large, Mr Dwimmersmith - then put on this blindfold and when you bump into a tree, just give the rope four short tugs and I'll be right along. Even if it's been a full ten minutes of a walking, an hour, two hours, or so on, don't stop until you bump into a tree. And if you hear any animal noises or footsteps, don't worry - the Weasley twins left a few invisible everlasting flying cassette players when they last came, and I haven't been able to find all of them."

The forest canopy was thick enough for the sky to be completely occluded, but nevertheless, the forest was well-lit with an indistinct greenish glow. There was a conspicuous lack of leaves on the ground, which made the area look like a creepily well-maintained lawn. "Right, let's do this," said Ozland.

#####

A quarter of an hour later, Ozland was completely fucking terrified.

He'd thought it would be easy enough after the first minute of walking forward with no eyesight in an environment that he knew had solid obstacles everywhere, listening only to the sounds of his own footsteps (and, occasionally other, very quiet footsteps).

But no, it really, really didn't get any easier, especially since he knew he'd bump into a tree anytime now.

The sound of a macaw, and then a squealing pig, echoed in the distance, and he shivered.

He'd been trying to think about the valoroscale. What if he'd written 'The Celestial Unorthodox Church will give, to the bearer of this note, one ounce of gold on May 15, 1996' - was the valoroscope somehow prescient, or only giving a best estimate? Probably the second, because otherwise they wouldn't be used on Gringotts counters, because Gringotts would be ruling the world rather than levying fees for standing in one place for too long. Was it a probability-weighted average value or the most likely value? Where did the knowledge for its best estimate come from? He supposed he could find out by writing 'The C.U.C will give, to the bearer of this note, ten Sickles - if, and only if, President Labar wins Chihuahua in the next election' - if it was 'zero' or 'ten Sickles', it would be 'most likely value', and if it was 'two Sickles and eleven Knuts', it would be an averaged value - and it would also indicate that the valoroscope didn't really have precise advanced knowledge of future events. If it was zero or ten Sickles, he still wouldn't really know - and, afterall, it wouldn't be too easy to distinguish between being really good at extrapolating the future versus actually knowing it. Unless, perhaps, there was a way to set up a totally random binary event, one that was completely disconnected from prior -

There was a loud clunk as Ozland's blindfolded head connected with the trunk of a tree. He dutifully tugged at the rope four times and took off the blindfold. "There has to be a better way to do this," he groaned, before returning to his original train of thought, sitting down at the base of the tree. Alright, future knowledge aside, how else could I use a valoroscope? There wasn't really much else he could think of, aside from the obvious thing which it had been built for. Assessing mineral resources over areas of land? The contents of safes? Discerning between real and fake diamonds? Evaluating insurance contracts, patents, corporate shares, and yet-to-be released books would probably fall under 'future knowledge'.

Ollivander was along quickly enough. "This one, eh?" he brought out a small chiseling tool, breaking off a fragment of the wood and holding it up to his left eyepiece. "Walnut and dittany stalk, an interesting combination, I suppose. Walnut often has an affinity for, well, people who push beyond, shall we say. Spellcrafting, rituals, dimensional arithmancy. Dittany stalk, on the other hand, is really for people more inclined towards Divination. An interesting combination indeed - Reginald Rookwood's wand was walnut and dittany."

"Is that a famous person?"

"Only the ritualist who inadvertently created the Cup of Magic and altered the course of magical society forever to come, Mr Dwimmersmith. Not that that would be a very sensible thing to aim towards. In any case," he said, changing the topic, "how many wands do you want? Ten Sickles each, and in all likelihood, you won't be able to find this tree again."

"How many Sickles to the Galleon?"

"Seventeen," Ollivander replied crisply.

A thousand undollars is about twenty Galleons is about four hundred Sickles, is forty wands. A thousand divided by forty is twenty-five undollars a wand - shit, that's about the price of an ice cream. He grinned. "Alright, I'll take thirty."

"Only thirty?"

Only thirty? Really?

At Ozland's confused look, he added: "The Cup has more than enough output to sustain a human Transfiguration for all of eternity - Albus is in his twelfth decade, and Minerva turned sixty this year - surely you noticed that they . . . ?"

'Only thirty?' is only a sensible question if you're either overly cautious, or if you expect to live for a very long time, he realised.

"Excuse me," he said, weakly, "how long does a wand last on average, and how many wands do wizards usually buy?"

"Thirty years, if they're kept in good condition - twenty years if they're not, and of course they are pieces of wood, and just as liable to break. And to answer your second question, about a hundred."

Wizards expect to live for about two thousand years?

#####

"You didn't let him talk you into anything silly like buying a hundred wands, did you?" Professor McGonagall asked wearily, looking at the enormous box Ozland had tucked under his arm.

Ozland groaned. "It seemed sensible at the time."

She shook her head. "It always does."

Dumbledore was busy talking to a translucent, silver dog. "Lord Speengrack, I can assure you that Augusta will be very amenable towards your amendment to the ink importation proposal - Minerva and I happen to be with a student at the moment, so we'll have to put this discussion on hold for the time being."

"Very well," said the dog in a deep, gruff voice, before disappearing.

"Excellent," said Dumbledore, clapping his hands. "Onwards we march." Ozland silently filed the translucent dog under 'questions to ask some time later but not now', as they walked out the door of Ollivanders and stopped in the middle of the street. "Onwards we march - or rather, onwards you march, Mr Cunningham - Minerva and I have urgent business at Hogwarts, Mrs Weasley will help you pick up the rest of your supplies."

"Alright."

"As a matter of fact," Dumbledore continued, glancing at his watch (which, Ozland had noticed by this point, didn't have any hands), "the Weasley door should be just around the next corner if we catch it now, but we'll have to be quick about it."

They cut a brutal diagonal through the foot traffic and came to a tall edifice that was entirely covered in doors. Dumbledore and Professor McGonagall didn't seem to be off-put by the lack of stairs, and instead walked forward to stand on a welcome mat in front of one of the door-columns. They looked at him expectantly, and he respectfully complied with what was bound to be the latest episode of madness in magical Britain.

Dumbledore twirled his wand. "Weasley family residence," he said.

All of a sudden, jazzy elevator music began to play, and the welcome mat began ascending into the air with a whoosh. Each ding brought them one door higher. Ozland counted the dings, growing more and more apprehensive as the sounds from the street below grew more distant, and as the sound of the rushing wind grew louder, counting ten, then twenty, then fifty, before the welcome mat finally stopped at the seventy-fourth ding, floating up and down unsteadily - and it still wasn't at the very top. The scarlet door they had stopped at had, strangely enough, had the Volkswagen logo etched onto the front, with 'Weasley Motors' in gold letters just underneath.

"Expecto patronum," Dumbledore murmured. An enormous silvery bird appeared, and Ozland almost stumbled off the welcome mat, and probably would have fallen to his death, had Professor McGonagall not put a steadying hand on his shoulder. "Tell Molly that we're here with Ozland." The bird nodded and swooped off.

" . . . two questions, what was that, and what's the Volkswagen logo doing on the door?"

Professor McGonagall seemed to have gotten the hang of answering questions without creating more. "A messenger spell, and that would be the symbol for Weasley Motors, who make flying automobiles - it's on all of their cars."

The door clicked open. Ozland was all too eager to get off the floating welcome mat, and was surprised to find himself standing on grass. He looked back at where he'd come from, and was even more surprised to find that they'd come out the door of what appeared to be an outhouse, that the sky above them didn't have any moons, that they were standing in a wide open space, and that in front of him was were what, he could only presume, were three houses trying to make baby-houses with one another, who, in the throes of brickwork passion, had become permanently wedged together into a six-story-high architectural monstrosity. The red-haired woman speed-walking towards them could only be -

"Ah, Mrs Weasley, how good to see you again!" rumbled Dumbledore.

"Is this the handsome young fellow picking up his supplies for Hogwarts?"

"Indeed," said Dumbledore, his eyes twinkling, "Minerva and I have urgent business at Hogwarts, unfortunately - Hagrid was a little unvigilant with his florkpurfle nest, and they'll be a few hours away from reaching the Type Three superintelligence stage . . . "

Mrs Weasley nodded sympathetically. "Don't you worry a thing, Albus. I'll just need to drag the children out shopping - oh, Ozland, why don't you come along?"

"Alright," Ozland was still craning his neck to look for a moon. Might as well ask now. "Er, why's there no Moon?"

"We had to move from Ottery St Catchpole during the War," Mrs Weasley said, slightly stiffly, "there wasn't enough time to find a universe-fragment with a moon in it. Anyway," she brightened, "take care of yourselves, Albus, Minerva." They nodded, and disappeared in a puff of displaced air.

She turned back to Ozland. "Want some lunch before we head out?"

#####

"Early court documents as interpreted by Hölmstrom et al. indicate that the Zauberkanzler of the Duchy of Bavaria (essentially equivalent to the Great Enchanter of Britain) formed the early underground society named the 'Illuminati', lead by Hauptberater ('Chief Advisor' Wilhelm Eldrich Illuminati) on 1 May, 1776, the members of which primarily consisted of Wizards, formally opposing Muggle superstition and religious influence. Informally, the aim of the Illuminati was to fool Muggles into a system of Enlightenment beliefs known as 'rationality', such that they would be less likely to attempt witch-hunts and dismiss evidence of the existence of Magic as 'irrational'…"

- Julipe H. Patrégon — Superstition in 18th Century European Society: Wizarding-Muggle Relations (1981, [abbrev.] — Mopfthord Acad. Press)

#####

NIGHT, AUGUST 24, 1995, LONG ISLAND ROAD, MONGOL TERRITORY, AUCKLAND, NEW ZEALAND

A balding man with a blue vein running down the side of his face dozed, asleep on an armchair on a balcony.

Distantly, crickets chirped and waves crashed along the beach.

A yellow lantern swung, hanging from the banister, making shadows dance in the darkness.

All of a sudden, very quietly, two hooded figures wearing necklaces popped into existence on the balcony.

The sleeping man snorted, turned to one side, and awoke with a start, fumbling around for his gun and squinting. He took in the balcony around him, scrutinising every corner, not seeing the hooded figures for some strange reason.

"Somnium," whispered one of the figures, taller than the other, with a lock of blonde hair poking out the side of his hood.

A slight glimmer struck the man in the chest. The man slumped over as the light hit him, forced into a stupor.

"Alright, Gil," said the shorter figure, in a low, measured voice, "do your thing, I'll handle his bones."

In the low light, the other figure flashed a grin. He had dazzling white teeth.

#####

Chapter 6: A Painting Inside A Painting

A/N: It's been almost two months since I published the last chapter. Life caught up and I realised my schedule of one chapter every two weeks was much too ambitious. I took some time off to plan out the rest of the story.

To recap, Ozland has just been in Dumbledore's office after bidding the Weasleys adieu, undergone the very-cleverly-written Ritual of the Time Cube, and woken up back in New Zealand.

#######
CHAPTER SIX
#######

[...]

STALIN:

I cannot abide by your superstition.

WIZARD:

Then I must repeat to you once more, our craft is ineffable,

And moreover not intended to be understood by man.

STALIN:

All is within the grasp of man! I have confidence that

In time man shall puncture the very firmament of the heavens

And violate the kingdom of God Himself.

WIZARD:

Such ambitions have been shared by cities whose names

Now read on tombstones.

STALIN:

Yet we are not a city, we are a civilisation.

WIZARD:

And as a city is to a civilisation, so will be past catastrophes

To the catastrophe that will inevitably result!

STALIN:

This magic, it resists scientific experimentation so?

WIZARD:

Tell me of what you mean by that term

Which rings so strangely to my ears.

STALIN:

It is to find within the turmoil of the universe

An underlying order; to lay bare the structure of

The celestial storm that surrounds us. It is

To find Newton in the path of Neptune,

Darwin in the Galapagos, and Marx in market capitalism.

It is to discern the nature of the cosmos and its atoms,

The arrangement of matter which gives rise to higher forms.

WIZARD:

I am afraid, dear General Secretary, that you shall find

That there is no underlying order to be found. That the

Inscrutability of wizardry will bring you to new heights

Of madness and frustration, as it has done to many before you.

Many have, of course, discovered arcane principles which

May be applied by practitioners of the craft, but I think

That you shall find that the low-hanging fruit have already

Been plucked, and that, in attempting to reach higher,

You may have an accident with your ladder and hurt yourself.

STALIN:

Then it is not only gold you ask for, but the suspension

Of our innate curiosity? A heavy price indeed.

WIZARD:

To sate one's curiosity before the well-beings of one's countrymen

Is perhaps a selfish and treacherous venture.

STALIN:

It is for their sakes that I wonder, not out of any selfish vice.

WIZARD:

Wonder?

STALIN:

The basis of our socialist system is the perfection

Of industrial techniques. To fully understand the principles

Which underlie the steam engine and the spinning loom

Is an important thing indeed. Without an understanding,

How can we perfect? Bereft of understanding, we would be

Condemned to see ourselves stagnate and stumble.

We cannot build communism through stumbling, hence

My concern over the implications of this supernatural marvel.

But more still, it would undermine the faith of every Soviet citizen

In the certitude of scientific fact, cast doubt on what mankind

Has so-far illuminated. What, say, of the principles

Of electromagnetism given the existence of Lumos?

What of the conservation of matter, given the existence of

A simple water-making Charm? Surely you can see how

Such a revelation would dampen the spirit of progress

And open the floodgates of religious reactionism!

WIZARD:

Then I must suggest, if the possibility has not

Already occurred to you, to walk on two feet.

STALIN:

Please elaborate.

WIZARD:

While magic will make every burden lighter by a thousandfold,

Your Muggle sciences will attempt to lighten every burden

Using reason rather than received lore. Eventually,

Should the words you have spoken to me be true,

A transition would begin, in which magic would be supplanted

By superior technological advances.

STALIN:

I must discuss it with Molotov.

[...]

– Belarusian University of the Arts play entitled 'Stalin's Dilemma' (performed 1986, translated by Yazhk [Dogthinker, Class III])

#######

"Imitative and unnecessarily florid. The heavy hand of Gosteleradio and Bolshoy's Dogthinkers have clearly dealt us another propaganda play." – radioyerevananswers885

"Angelika Savelievna's performance as Stalin was inspired." – Martsin Aleksiutovič, steel-worker, associate professor of sociology at the B.U.A

"[...] an exploration of a collision between dialectical materialism and the seemingly-insurmountable ideological challenge of magic that proved utterly tantalising." – Critic, Dogthinker [Class V]

"If this gets adapted into film, I would be happy to consult." – Joseph Vissarionovich Stalin [VERIFIED USER]

#######

THE SAME DAY – GORDON COATES MEMORIAL PARK, TERRITORY OF THE CELESTIAN UNORTHODOX CHURCH, AUCKLAND, NEW ZEALAND

"Well I'm sorry, Oz, since I've been trying to fucking reach you for the last five hours to tell you someone leaked Rushabh's suicide to the press before we could set up the official story and that, in accordance with time-honoured tradition, his fucking Unsealing Ceremony, you know, the one where they read out his successor for the position of Jupiter-Minister of the whole of New Zealand, is happening in Gordon Coates in twenty minutes and we're on the fucking guest-list."

"Oh," said Ozland.

"Yes," said Evelyn. "I thought you might say something like that."

Something felt wrong.

The procession was small and formal and held on the flat top of a hill overlooking a garden of flowers. A squat, marbly-coloured box could be found where an open casket would have been.

A man in factory-blue overalls went around, solemnly offering everyone a scoop of black ice-cream in memory of the recently departed, courtesy of Tip Top Ltd. Evelyn didn't know what flavour it would be. She suspected it would either be licorice or charcoal, and so politely declined.

As she and Ozland walked through the concentric semicircles to take their seats, the apprehensive voices became a low, subdued murmur like a pot being taken off a stovetop, going from boiling to simmering. There was a note of tension in the air. The CEO of Tip Top glanced at her, and when she turned to look back at him, he was staring resolutely forward.

As she sat, Ozland began shaking hands with people. He went from Wu Xilai, Commissar of External Affairs of the Red Dragons, to some high-ranking Nisango member to Henry van Nanseer, a mysterious-looking ThauCorp exec, all sitting in the innermost row. His handshake, Evelyn noted, could do with a little more work, but it seemed to have an almost hypnotic effect. The semicircles were divided down the middle by a black carpet, and after Ozland had finished shaking hands with everyone in the innermost row, he ambled down the carpet, briefly touching the nearest chair of each row. The tension began to unravel. The world exhaled. Everything was going to be alright.

(It was par for the course for semi-public gatherings like these, but Evelyn was slightly embarrassed to see a few people in the outermost rows attempt to discreetly touch their fingers to Ozland's cloak, as if divinity brushed off.)

And then he came back, and sat in the seat, and everything was completely silent.

Someone from the middle-row, probably the Mars-Minister of Rituals, rose and brought himself to the centre of the congregation. The Rituals Minister cleared his throat, a small, bleating noise, and began. "I stand before all of you in a special position, both as the executor to Rushabh's Celestian Will, and as," he said, too proudly for Evelyn's taste, "the Mars-Minister of Rituals for the North Shore City Region." He went on, listing trivial, unimportant things, stroking his beard self-importantly.

"So, this is it, isn't it?" It was a question, but Ozland had said it flatly – not that there was much intonative nuance you could put into a whisper.

"Chin up, Oz. You're about to make it big-time."

"Well, Rushabh might've passed the Jupiter-Ministership onto you," Ozland replied glassily. That stings.

"Just in case your absinthe-induced nostalgia-fog is preventing you from remembering things properly, he was off his damn nut," she shot back. "He might've passed it onto Kev. Or the Minister of Justice. Or some woman who did his fucking dry-cleaning back in '85."

"He wouldn't've."

"Of course he would not have," Evelyn made sure to enunciate each of the words individually, "he almost started a second game of nuclear chicken with the Church just to get you your General Affairs Ministership, so was there any point to you saying I might be the next Jupiter-Minister or did you just say that to be a hungover asshole?"

"I didn't mean it that way."

"Then how did you mean it?"

He apparently couldn't think of anything to say to that.

Evelyn sat back, satisfied, while the Minister of Rituals droned onward. She glared at him, tapping her watch suggestively.

The Minister cut off into a strangled silence. "– er, and he did many good things later on in his life, I'm sure. Rushabh came to New Zealand from Indonesia as a nuclear technician and departed our world as a cherished, senior figure in the Church, and other things along those lines, et cetera, et cetera. I wouldn't want to, er, detain such an esteemed congregation for longer than necessary, so I'll get to the Unsealing, shall I?" he laughed nervously.

Everyone brought out their earmuffs during a long, uncomfortable time in which the Rituals Minister took to the box with a gargantuan half-chisel half-hammer. There has to be a more effective way to seal a Celestian Will, other than putting it in a box. An intemperate elderly gentleman four seats to her left looked as if he were about to stand up indignantly and leave the Unsealing, but evidently decided it would be too awkward. His moustache jerked about on his face like an angry burlesque dancer.

The woman sitting to her right, the wife of the Chief Financial Officer of the Mongol Private Defense Corporation, slouched, fanning herself. "How long do these usually take?" she asked Evelyn in a loud drawl.

"Depends," Evelyn replied, having already decided that she disliked the woman's attitude, which she had evaluated separately from her being a 77-Church-following God-damned heathen whore bitch gold-digger who would inevitably be vaporized by the Celestians when the End Times came. "It's a hyper-regular metalloid nanocrystalline case from ThauCorp's labs."

"What the hell is that supposed to mean?"

"Means it doesn't melt or buckle or warp, it shatters. All of the ridges, faults, and stress-lines from the . . . tool," she was on a fucking streak of knowledgeability and if she didn't know what the half-hammer half-chisel thing was called, it was its own fault for being so damn obscure, "nothing happens for a while, maybe a minute, two, five, ten, twenty – and then suddenly it bursts into little pieces like glass."

Madam Mignani had smoothly transitioned from obliviously gazing at the box to watching it in terror, jerking involuntarily with every hammer-chisel blow.

"There are some extra seats near the back," said Evelyn kindly. "And everyone's already seen you sitting in the front so it won't be a status blow or anything if you're worried about that."

She huffed. It was a remarkably articulate huff. It was a huff that declared 'I'm so high status I don't even have to worry about status'. The heathen-woman picked up her handbag and left soon after.

Evelyn smiled.

That was when the box shattered.

##

"So, it's the big day, huh?" Henry van Nanseer was almost jubilant as they shook hands.

"No idea what you mean," Ozland said, crisply.

The exec snorted. "The demented old fuck is dead, and we all know he favoured you as his successor. Drop the faux obliviousness."

"I'll thank you," he spoke in a low voice, "not to refer to the former Jupiter-Minister of the Celestian Unorthodox Church as a 'demented old fuck'. Rushabh was a mentor of mine, and I was very close to him."

Van Nanseer winked, but as Ozland held his cold glare, his face quickly fell blank. "My comments were inappropriate and uncalled for," he rattled off, "as a representative of ThauCorp's many New Zealand-based subsidiaries, I apologise wholly and unreservedly. We hope to keep doing business with the new regime." The exec paused, and then reached into his jacket. He took out a card and handed it to Ozland. "Could I give you my business card so we can keep in touch?"

Ozland held the card in his hand. It was cream-coloured with golden edges. He glanced back at Evelyn, who was busy dealing with an obnoxious Dragon-affiliated reporter, talking smoothly while making the 'please deal with this person' code-sign behind her back. Eventually an unsympathetic-looking pair of guards gently lead the reporter away. That Rushabh had killed himself was both good and bad: good in that foul-play wouldn't be suspected, and bad in that it wouldn't cast the upper echelons of the Celestian Church in a very favourable light. Evelyn must be pissed. I wonder how it got out?

"No, I'm afraid not." He flicked the card into the grass. Another moment of concentration, and it erupted into flames. It was good to remind people sometimes. Leaving an open-mouthed Henry van Nanseer behind him, he exchanged bland pleasantries with diplomats, statespeople, weapons dealers, gang leaders, ice cream execs, and donors, who all became a steady blur of suits and expensive watches. It barely required any thought at all, no more than walking or breathing.

It gave him some time to think, to push the dreadful unreality that was Hogwarts out of his mind. He'd maintained that wonderful illusion for a few minutes, thinking that maybe he could maintain his tenuous sanity by pretending it had all been a dream, before he'd rushed back indoors after Evelyn had hurled abuse at him, looking for his formal wear. In doing so, he discovered a merlot-red satchel, filled with all of his wands and all of his textbooks, left with a little note from Dumbledore whose exact wording he couldn't remember now. It was a potent reminder that nothing could ever be the way it had been before. In the early morning, there had been Rushabh's suicide. In the late morning, the defector-priest began floating around and recounting his alien-abduction story. And then, of course, in the evening, the owls had delivered him the letters.

You should be crying, or something, said an insistent voice in his head.

I don't really feel any need to cry.

So you don't feel sad that Rushabh died?

The thought occurred to him that no, he didn't. The thought bounced around inside his skull, becoming more and more hysterical. He didn't feel sad, or bad, or anything. He hadn't been drinking last night. In fact, up until he'd woken up at his house, he'd completely forgotten about Rushabh. Was that normal?

Maybe the naive eight-year-old Ozland still believed Rushabh's soul had been absorbed into the Collective Unconscious and that he hadn't died at all, that all he would have to do would be to wait for the Celestians to transport the followers of the Church to Planet Celestia and then Rushabh would be there, wondering what took him so damn long and would he go fetch another beer from the fridge?

A hush descended, and the Mars-Minister of Rituals came up to the front to deliver his speech. He could sense the oppressive, titanic weight of inevitability bearing down on him. He felt utterly powerless.

"So this is it, isn't it?"

##

The Rituals Minister brought out a long scroll. A beat of hesitation before –

"Evelyn Rawter."

"Yes?"

"That's what's on the paper," the Minister's face was gray and slightly sickly. "Evelyn Catherine Matchwell Rawter."

What?

She hadn't prepared for this, not at all.

Ozland looked merely perplexed, but kept clenching and unclenching his jaw in a way that suggested to Evelyn that the proclamation had rattled him deeply.

It occurred to her that everyone was staring in her direction. Say something, dammit!

She stood up. "This is highly irregular, but I will ensure that the succession proceeds smoothly and with minimal disruption."

Perhaps the words had flown out of her mouth a little too effortlessly. Ozland glanced up at her suspiciously, he probably suspected it was planned. But there wasn't anything wrong with preparedness, was there?

And then the realisation struck her with full force. I'm the Jupiter-Minister. She had to repeat it a few times like an affirmation, otherwise she wouldn't believe it.

Evelyn looked around. It felt as if there was some other thing, some other element that would be needed to complete –

"I assent to and fully support Miss Rawter's ascension to the Jupiter-Ministership," said Ozland glibly. "Rushabh's choice was unexpected, but I am relieved to see that the stewardship of the New Zealand division of the Celestian Unorthodox Church has been placed in capable hands. I will not contest the Ministership at this point."

Astonished silence turned into a hubbub of frenzied discussion. Cameras flashed from the back.

"Ozland, you're a goddamned idiot."

"What?"

"At this point?"

"Yes," he said, "at this point."

Evelyn rubbed her eyes, sitting down. "This is a fucking mess. You read the crowd right – they wanted something from you, but the way you did it suggests a whole equal-power dynamic. And then you had to add 'at this point' which basically says you're waiting for your opportunity to seize back the throne."

"I'm not – "

"The Church does not do unstable, the Church does not do drama. We present an image of strict internal unity, and we make an example out of people who don't tow the line. We have a single leader who is the central locus of the movement and their two lieutenants, not a dual-power system or a triad!"

"Jesus, Ev, calm down!"

She laughed bitterly. "Aha, cold, condescending, cool-cucumber Ozland. Don't fucking pretend to be the voice of reason, why the fuck aren't you more worried?"

"I . . . " Ozland seemed genuinely lost. "I don't know. I should be. I just . . . all of this," he sighed, leaning forward and cupping his hands together. His voice came out almost in a whisper. "I feel like I'm walking through a dream. You know I don't believe in, well, Him anymore, how do you think I felt when the priest who defected from the 77 Church started floating around in the interrogation room?"

"I would think that you would reconsider your unfaith and have more appreciation for the gifts that God has given you during your time on Earth."

"Maybe that was the intended result."

"Huh?"

"Look, shit, just ignore me. What happens next?"

She had to think about that one. "Today? Nothing. I'll stay on as Mars-Minister of Propaganda and Public Relations, you'll stay on in General Affairs. Tomorrow? God knows."

A series of beeps came from Ozland's pocket. He glanced at his pager. "Kevin wants to meet with me at Denny's, probably wants to rant at me again. Peace and love, I guess," he said, the standard greet-and-goodbye for Unorthodoxists. Ozland turned to leave, and carelessly elbowed his way through the stream of people leaving the service.

She waved a brief, polite goodbye. "Peace and love," she called out.

##

DENNY'S FAMILY RESTAURANT, WESTHAVEN HIGH-DENSITY URBAN LIVING ACCOMMODATION, NEW ZEALAND

The Denny's had molded itself to their daily meetings in the same way that the passage of air gradually erodes canyons. The prices of all the dishes they usually ordered had lowered over time. There was a straight line from the door to Table 14 with nothing else in the way (with the exception of the forest of potted plants that occluded it from all sides), and there were five slight indentations in the squishy seat around the circular table. The table itself could best be described as abstract art in the medium of coffee stains.

Kevin waited outside.

Ozland found him and all of his mannerisms utterly fascinating. He was always tapping his feet, unless he was talking. The longer you talked, the faster the tapping became. Every half-minute, he glanced at his watch and pulled at his sleeves. Throughout a conversation, he always clasped his hands together and leant forward, and then a few moments later, he would lean back, rocking back and forth like someone trying to keep upright on a dinghy being tipped by waves. He had the harried, flustered look of someone in a perpetual hurry.

As he and Ozland walked through the doors, he quickly counted the number of red tiles on the restaurant floor in a rapid flurry of numbers under his breath and straightened every napkin as they went past each empty table. He was clearly angry as they went up to the counter to order.

"I'll have the special soup," Ozland said.

"Too loud, can't you get quieter food?"

"A tall smoothie, then."

"Same issue. Slurp slurp slurp."

Ozland wondered if Kevin had a melting point, or if he was like one of those chemicals which stayed solid up until a certain temperature and then suddenly sublimed into a gas.

"Deep-fried, extra crunchy spring-rolls."

"Again, too loud."

"Actually no, I'll have all three, and Kevin will have mashed potatoes."

Kevin's face melted into confusion, as if he hadn't figured out that Ozland was deliberately spiting him, but seemed satisfied with the mashed potatoes. The woman nodded, heaped abundant praise on Ozland for a bridge infrastructure project he'd never heard of, and said she would send the bill to the Church. They went to sit down.

Ozland folded his arms and flicked his wrist. Everything went silent. "So, what is it? More problems with importing pickles from the Trans-Pacific?"

Kevin splayed out his fingers and seemed to glance at each in turn. "No. The end-month pickle imports from the Trans-Pacific Railway proceeded as expected. Seventy-six point seven tonnes, cash payment of one hundred and fifteen thousand undollars from the buyers. Two percent transaction fee. The bidding process begins later this evening, and the proceeds will be subject to the standard twelve percent import fee which will be added to the Vaults within three days." He paused, as if mechanically shifting into a different gear. "You killed Rushabh."

Ozland frowned. "Excuse me?"

"Rushabhhad been regularly requesting antidepressant medication for the past six months," Kevin somehow managed to carry off both anger and disinterest, "I reviewed the records. He rarely made public appearances. He only met with us in the morning sporadically. When he did, he seemed hungover and always left early. You made a phone call to him the night before he killed himself."

"But you said that I killed him."

Kevin folded and unfolded his hands before speaking. "Semantics. Did the murderer kill the victim or was it his knife?"

"Fair. Keep going." Ozland leant back.

The Minister of Logistics was unperturbed. "You made a phone call to him the night before he killed himself. You were aware he was in a depressive state. He drinks very heavily on Sundays. You were aware that in all likelihood, he would pass the position of Jupiter-Minister onto you. You were also aware that the correct prompting could make him commit suicide. Evelyn told me how you looked yesterday, when he informed you about his death. She said you looked like you were in shock. But it is easy to mistake shock for casual indifference, or for that matter, foreknowledge." He continued. "People tend to interpret social cues contextually rather than as probabilistic representations of internal mental states, which is where I believe her error in judgement came from."

Alright, I think I've had enough of this. He shook his head, putting on a resigned expression. "So it was you!"

"Excuse me?" Kevin seemed affronted by the sudden shift.

"I can't believe I didn't make the connection before. As Minister of Logistics, you control the inflow and outflow of every pill and tablet in the country. Your parents are doctors, professors of medicine – you carefully charted every single one of Rushabh's mood swings, his low ebbs, his depressive bouts, his behaviour, how he spoke, when he left – there was no single other man in Auckland more acutely aware of Rushabh's state of mind than you, Kevin. And how undervalued you felt! A brilliant mind, atrophying in the subordinated bureaucratic jumble that is the position of the Mars-Minister of Logistics for the North Shore City Region – what tragedy!

"Everywhere you saw a system running off-time, unused, underutilisation and overutilisation, bloated departments, corrupt ministers, fat to trim – but what could a man chained to his office do? And then a fantastic idea struck you! Rushabh, Ozland, Evelyn, Dom – the Commanding Ministers, people listened to them, didn't they? They gave orders, people obeyed. What good you could do if only you had a higher role! So one night, you adulterated one of Rushabh's antidepressants, and oh, it was so easy – too easy, to push Rushabh off the edge of the cliff. He was a nuclear-armed madman at the end of his rope, no-one would suspect a single thing! But a problem emerged – Evelyn and I would obviously want to cover up the suicidal aspect of it, possibly broadcasting it as a political assassination, and the title would go to me, not you, with no controversy.

"So what better a plan than, upon hearing of Rushabh's as-expected death, to leak the news before we had time to prepare? To throw a wrench into the propaganda machine and disrupt the – "

"Enough!" Kevin roared, "Minister Cunningham," he continued in a quieter voice, as if unsure of himself, his eyes unusually tense, "you may think that you can successfully run the Church using deception and clever wordplay as a substitute for practical and sustainable governance. You have never known anything but power, and the idea that you could lose power through misunderstanding the hegemonic mechanisms and the day-to-day systems underlying the perpetuation of your power, is, so far as I can see, a concept alien to you. Your fantastic delusions have entranced the Church, its upper echelons, and its followers, save for myself." He tilted his head. "You will find that reality can only be fooled for so long, and when the day comes, when it refuses to be fooled more, I will be ready to step forward to return sanity to the Church."

Ozland jaw had tightened, by a fraction of an inch. Maybe my improvised piss-take had an element of truth. "My phone call was to do with the updated uniform designs. Please don't interrupt my busy schedule with pointless murder accusations in future and keep your personal dislike of me separate from your work as a civil servant, you fuckingslice of shit," he shouted, abruptly standing up. He realised he was shaking.

Kevin only stared into his drink.

Breathe in.

He left the table, brushing away the potted plants.

Four second hold.

He strode at a quick clip across the diner, attracting curious looks.

Slowly breathe out.

He reached the door.

Six second hold.

He flung open the door.

Repeat.

Ozland cupped his face in his hands, leaning back against the grubby facade of the building. He had come out into a corridor, eight floors up.

The wall he faced bore a neon blue sign, the symbol of the Unorthodox Church. It was the letter C, bisected with the Christian cross, like a cent symbol. Below it was a tiny photograph of Saint Matchwell, along with a stylised illustration of Evelyn, her sunglasses tilted down quizzically. He was there too, in the form of a political placard stapled into the drywall.

Hundreds of thousands had fled to New Zealand during the civil wars across the Pacific in the seventies. Hyperdense Urban Living Accommodations were Saint Matchwell's prescription for the resulting crisis: ten levels of three by three metre cells, a thousand on each floor. Fifty thousand times denser population-wise than the surrounding city, HULAs were effectively human sardine cans. Each floor had a chapter of the Church. Since alternative reading material was scarce, HULA children learned to read through the Matchwell Revelations and the Celestian Messages, which was all for the best, really, in the end.

Ozland glanced up at the roof. Was it porridge, matted seaweed, tofu, or all three? Most of the HULAs had never been officially finished – people brought in their own materials and continued where contractors had left off. The dividing walls between apartments had been knocked down to make long, winding passageways lit by crude fluorescent tubes.

Judging by their pale faces, many residents hadn't stepped outside their HULA in years. A single undollar note could circulate around inside a single unit for a decade before passing outside to be exchanged for fresh vegetables, oil, machine parts, and livestock. Some HULAs had their own cute little gangs which divided up sections of floors as territory and occasionally had cute little gang wars with cute little body-counts, he had been amused to learn.

I'm distracting myself. This is a mess, this is a fucking mess and I made the mess, why did I make this mess?

The sound of sloshing water echoed through the corridor, and a blonde woman walking her poodle came from around the corner. She stopped when she saw him.

"Cunningham?" the woman asked with a disinterested Australian drawl. The poodle yapped.

Ozland stared back at her and eventually nodded.

"I've been told to give this to you." She brought out a yellow parcel from her handbag. "Correspondence," she elaborated, putting a cigarette in her mouth. "Got a lighter?"

"The den is a few minutes away," Ozland said, turning over the parcel in his hands warily. "Why couldn't they just mail me over the Red Mundial?"

"I just give the parcels, sweetie," the woman replied, continuing her stroll down the dark passageway. "Take that up with them when you see them, huh?"

Them?

The mystery didn't last for very long. The message had been typewritten on blue-cornered office paper.

His name was handwritten along the top – a touch of personality, but Ozland still had the distinct sense that the letter was just an end-product, spat out of a vast, indifferent corporate machine with a trillion moving parts that he would never be able to comprehend. It was as impersonal as a tax form.

Dear Mr. Min. Gen. Affairs 'O Wise Ldr. Of The 1000 Stars Hgh. Priest Gd.-King Ozland Cunningham,

We request your presence to discuss the possibility of ThauDevelopment – A Subsidiary of ThauCorp acquiring land in an area currently under the jurisdiction of the Authority of the Celestian Unorthodox Church.

Please meet us at the standard location.

Yours graciously,

Henry van Nanseer

Chief of Internal Coordination

ThauDevelopment – A Subsidiary of ThauCorp

#######

LEVEL 808, CENTRAL OFFICE, THAUCORP DEVELOPMENTAL AREA

Ozland had identified it, the vague sense of unease. I'm off my game. It was Kevin's murder accusation that had been bothering him. Why would he make himself a target? Was he recording the conversation? What was the point of saying it in the first place? There were too many unknowns and not enough answers.

The trip to the ThauCorp Developmental Area only put him more on edge. There were rumours about the Developmental Area: enormous towers reaching into the sky, underground facilities, biological weapons testing, mysterious abandoned buildings with flickering lights – it was a positive cornucopia of conspiracy and intrigue.

Naturally, it was only allowed because neighbouring paragovs like the Celestian Church were making millions of pounds from ground rent. ThauCorp also provided a natural buffer against Ātete, an indigenous land-reclamation guerilla army with a penchant for sudden waves of aggression.

"Ozland?"

He realised he'd zoned out. "Yes?"

They were in an office on the 308th floor, from which only the evening sky was visible through the windows. They were seated around a rectangular blue table.

"As I was saying," van Nanseer continued, pouring a thick dossier of documents onto the tabletop, "we're looking to lease the northern portion of Glen Eden for the standard fifty-year period."

"Why?" Ozland asked, frowning. "It's not contiguous with the rest of the Developmental Area, is it?" And why not just rent it on a monthly basis? It indicated that the Board had become confident in the stability of the Church.

The businessman seemed confused. "It's contiguous with Sunnyvale and Kelston. Rushabh drew up the deal earlier last month."

What the hell? He pinched the bridge of his nose. "Alright, go on."

Van Nanseer looked at him strangely and coughed. "We're prepared to offer thirty million British pounds."

"One hundred million pounds," Ozland said automatically. "An eighth of that in gold futures, a quarter in Negaloth shares, and another quarter in five-year Soviet bonds. Can you arrange that?"

Van Nanseer smiled. "I'll take it to the board. Pleasure doing business with you, Cunningham."

"The same," he replied, still distracted.

He took the metro back to his house unaccompanied (Evelyn would scold him later) and collapsed into bed.

Something felt wrong.

#######

FEBRUARY 3, 1931 – LEVEL MINUS FOUR, MINISTRY OF MAGIC

For eight seconds, everything was still.

And then life continued. In Diagon Alley, glasses clinked in celebration of Emir Quarfaad's visit to Britain. In Hogsmeade, butterbeer disappeared with a heavy glug down the throats of wizards and witches. In Malfoy Manor, the nobility made polite conversation as clocks chimed to midnight, eight seconds late.

But the jubilant atmosphere stopped at the iron door of the Department of Mysteries.

In the corridors, there was a heightened sense of dread. Paranoia had infected every passageway. Voices were lowered. Words were whispered softly.

Thirty minutes later, the Head Unspeakable was pacing frantically about in his office, with the growing realization that someone had done something wrong, and he would be the one to be blamed.

"Time stopped for eight seconds? You're certain?"

"Very, sir," Rookwood replied.

"Anyone we can blame?"

Rookwood pondered this. "Samuels, probably, sir. Without the special clock he invented, we wouldn't have noticed it –"

The Department Director gave him a blank look. "The special clock?"

"– the one that measures the number of seconds per second –"

"Ah, yes."

"– and the chances are one in an obsquatumatillion it'll ever happen again, sir. Just a minor surge in the Cup's thaumic output causing a buffer overflow in the Ward of the Thirteen."

Rookwood watched as his superior sat himself down at the bloodoak desk, cleared away mounds of paperwork, and started thoughtfully drumming his fingers on the worn surface, before it began to float gently up towards the ceiling. The Director leant in on the desk in a natural motion, keeping it pinned down to the floor, and then started floating along with the desk. Unwilling to concede defeat, he seemed to come to the conclusion that no embarrassment could result if he simply ignored it. The wizard was a few centimetres above the ground when he suddenly opened up with a rapid-fire barrage of questions. "Splinches at the temporal interfaces?"

"No –"

"Divergences in thaumometer readings?"

"Nothi–"

"Leyline breakages?"

"None that we –"

"Have the Unseelie risen once more from the twisting fractal depths of Tir inna n-Og?"

"Er . . . no?"

"So, to be clear," the Head Unspeakable intoned, floating still higher, "nothing, nothing which we would, in our duties as guardians of ancient lore, gatekeepers of eldritch horrors beyond the mortal ken of man, tamers of the raging primordial elemental forces, etcetera etcetera etcetera, nothing which we would be obliged to inform the Minister of in the upcoming budgetary session?"

"Well . . . I'll have to fill out a form, sir. Unintentional temporal malpractice. I, er, faintly recall," Rookwood said. (He was familiar enough with the form to have caught himself subconsciously tracing its outlines in the fogged window by his desk.)

"Good, good," the Director muttered distractedly, his head slowly nearing the ceiling. "I'm sure you're aware of what this looks like, Rookwood. It looks like we're overstepping the boundaries. It looks like we're mismanaging our mysticism, debauching our divine powers –"

"– I'm sure, sir –"

"– abusing the occult, exploiting our esotericism –"

"– I think I understand –"

"– perverting prophecy, ouch, corrupting our karm . . . er . . . karmicosity . . . yes, indeed." The wizard straightened his glasses, and sighed, head now planted firmly in plasterboard. From below, he had all the seeming of a bureaucrat ascended to a higher managerial plane of being. "Ward of the Thirteen, Ward of the Thirteen. Rookwood, why does that name ring a bell?"

"Erm, it's the ward that supports all the other wards, sir," Rookwood said, wondering if it would've been considered impolite to look up. "Merlin and a bunch of other fancy wizards whipped it up in the one-hundreds. It was, er, originally erected to defend us from the ice-mages of Orendel but, well, feature creep, I suppose. According to the ancient scrolls we looked at, the time-stopping component was meant to temporarily halt Daevite encroachment, but the only thing we found on the Daevites in the Department Archival Library was a small black book with a note stuck to it which said to never read it or bring it within fifteen metres of human blood."

"And this . . . defense mechanism . . . activated . . . why?"

Rookwood coughed. "The ward's only rated for twenty trillion thaums, but ever since we plugged the Cup into the central Nexus, it's been getting much more juice than it's rated for. The Great Enchanter was holidaying in Belgium when it happened so he dismissed it – otherwise we'd have been frozen forever."

"That bloody Cup has been causing a fair share of nuisance, hasn't it? Why don't we just smash the ruddy thing up?"

"Olymp Kagnarr from the ICW's Bad Things Division says if the Cup so much as gets knocked over, it would melt the Earth and a few other things besides."

The Director jolted in his seat. "Merlin, we have a potential Earth-and-other-things-besides-destroying artifact here?"

"Um, yes."

"Make sure to mention it in the budgetary session. I want them to know I'm as mad as a Mudlomper, unhinged as a broken door, semi-psychotic, away with the færies, and ready to melt the Earth and a few other things besides at a moment's notice, and then we'll see how long it takes for them to cut a few thousand Galleons from the damn DMLE."

"Noted. In the meanwhile, should I look into ways to discharge the thaumic surplus, perhaps to some trusted third parties?"

#######

Dear Editor,

I am SHOCKED and APPALLED at the HORRENDOUS quality of this year's home appliances! My light fixtures have stopped working, my deep freeze refuses to operate, my radio is stuck on one channel, and my toaster EXPLODED in a shower of sparks yesterday! In fact, not a SINGLE electrical device in my entire household is functioning properly.

SHAME on British corporations who use CHEAP and NASTY manufacturing methods!

So far, only Negaloth's appliances have proved functional and what a BEAUTY they are! Negaloth was kind enough to replace all of my appliances with patented Negaloth technology.

I urge readers to purchase ONE Negaloth device and see how BRILLIANTLY they operate.

Kind Regards,

Margaret Gullikson

– March 5, 1936 (Dorset Gazette)

#######

HOGWARTS, SCOTTISH HIGHLANDS, REPUBLIC OF SCOTLAND – THE HERE AND NOW

Dawn came to Hogwarts. It washed over the gardens, tickled the stonework, brushed the tips of the towers, and eventually struck Ozland in the face with full force.

His first bizarre thought as he woke up was that he had been imprisoned. The walls, ceiling, and floor were all stone. Apparently, somehow he'd been taken back to Hogwarts and these would be his accommodations.

The one window, off in the far corner, was done in coloured glass: a knight wildly swinging a sword at a green dragon. As he looked closer, the dragon roared, and tessellated shards of red and orange glass erupted from its mouth. When he looked next, the dragon and the knight had rolled out a piece of cloth and were picnicking together on top of the hill. Then, once the last crystalline sandwich had been eaten, they were back at it again with renewed vigour.

Shaking his head, Ozland got out of bed. He looked around the room more. There was a door at the end, of course, but it was otherwise bare.

He went up to the coloured glass and tapped it. "Oi you, where're the showers?"

The small knight figure motioned at the door with its sword, but otherwise seemed to ignore him.

The door only lead to a corridor, and the corridor lead to a main passageway of sorts, layered with paintings on either side. Ozland was surprised there had been enough people in all of wizarding Britain's history to paint portraits of, although, he supposed, some of them might have been made up by the artists. (Which in turn implied that whatever process was used to make new paintings also created fully-fledged consciousnesses with their own memories and personalities as a byproduct.)

"I suppose I ought to ask again," he said.

"Ask what?" came a reply from his left. The voice sounded distant and had a slight reverb.

He looked to his left: there was a glum painting of a dimly-lit corridor, much like the one he'd come down. Hung up on one of its walls, rimmed with gold, done in little brushstrokes, was a tiny painting inside the painting – a princess, from what he could tell, dressed in florid blue. "Where are the showers?" he asked, fascinated.

"Come again?"

"Where are the showers?" Ozland said again, much louder.

"Oh," said the princess-painting, "you'll have to excuse me, the acoustics in this hall aren't that good. And why in the name of Merlin would you want to have a shower like a commoner?"

"What else would I do?"

"The Clean-Up Charm, naturally," the meta-painting replied, seeming confused.

"I don't know it."

"It's simple. Say 'Lasciato', and then do this."

"Do what?"

"What I'm doing with my wand right now, you dolt."

"Er, the brushstrokes aren't fine enough for me to see what's going on," Ozland said, embarrassed. "Just looks like a blurry squiggle to me."

The princess sighed. "I'll have to fetch the Meta-Man."

"Who?"

"The man who can go up and down painting levels."

" . . . how many of those are there, exactly?"

The meta-painting seemed to consider this. "Well, about eight hundred going down – I'm not sure how many there are going up, though. Are you a painting, by any chance?"

"Er, I don't think so."

"Think so or know so? And do you want me to fetch the Meta-Man or not?"

"If you would be so kind."

The princess left her frame, presumably in search of the mysterious Meta-Man.

It didn't take too long. The perspective of the painting started to look more and more wrong. Black lines bled and perspectives bulged, colours collapsed into sickly gray-greens. The brushstrokes in the painting began to wriggle like earthworms, knotting and melting until the Meta-Man took shape.

The Meta-Man, Ozland thought, wasn't really a man. He was a grotesque, brutal geometric abstraction, covered in charcoal veins. Nine pairs of blinking eyes roiled about on his body. The only thing that made him barely human was a red business-tie running down his front. Looking at him filled Ozland with the irrational fear that someday he would find out how to bleed into the real world.

As he watched with horrified intrigue, the Meta-Man somehow drew himself a hand, which then drew a brush, which drew another hand, and then a wide, thick-lipped mouth filled with uneven teeth. And then finally, a wand.

One of the Meta-Man's eyes drifted across its body to look at the princess-painting, who motioned with her wand. The Meta-Man copied. A twirl, then a vertical line from top to bottom.

"Lasciato," it growled. The canvas of the painting rippled and bulged.

"Thanks for all the help," Ozland half-squeaked, darting down the passageway.

###

After some time, tracing back his steps, Ozland realised he was lost. It was absurd – it had only been five minutes or so of wandering down a straight hall, but when he looked for the corridor he'd come from, he only found a grotty stairwell that kept on descending and descending until it came to an abrupt dead-end with an oil painting of an artist with a curly moustache, painting a self-portrait. Water dripped from the low ceiling.

"Excuse me," he said to the artist, almost only to break the dreadful silence, "I'm lost."

The artist kept painting, ignoring him until: "And where would you be trying to get to?"

It had the vaguest hint of a French accent.

"I don't know," Ozland replied, "I was hoping you'd help me figure that out, too."

"Ah," the painted-artist said, dipping its brush into violet gouache, "then you must first know what you want."

"Um, okay, that's useful advice in general, I guess – I just want breakfast."

"Go up the stairs, go down the corridor, and turn eight lefts."

At this point, Ozland wasn't going to bother questioning it. "Turn eight fucking lefts," he muttered under his breath, breaking into a jog.

The architecture of Hogwarts, however, was unwilling to accommodate the simplicity of lefts and rights. The end of one candle-lit corridor had a clear 90-degree left turn, but as he rushed closer and closer, it began straightening out, and by the time he'd reached it, it was a rightward U-bend that turned into a spiral stairwell. He opted to walk backward since technically it would still count as a left, and every revolution of the stairwell would be another turn.

And so he ended up crashing into Dumbledore, who was walking up the stairs.

"Ah, Ozland," he boomed, "a fortunate coincidence. Professor Trelawney is expecting us."

"I was just looking for breakfast – "

Dumbledore twiddled his fingers, and a white dining plate accompanied by a knife and a fork fell from nowhere, settling to float in front of him. The wizard proceeded to reach into the pockets of his robe, pulled out an unlabelled can, opened it, and poured steaming baked beans onto the plate. "Everlasting baked beans," he said, by way of explanation, "one of the exceptions to the Principal Exceptions to Gamp's Law," and began snapping his fingers.

Two sausages, a hash brown, a poached egg, and a small saucer filled with green stew fell neatly onto the plate with each snap.

"Thanks," Ozland murmured, following Dumbledore. The plate kept hovering in front of him, and as soon as he'd reached the top of the stairs, he began digging in. (He wasn't confident that he could safely eat with a knife and fork and walk up a stairwell at the same time.)

They reached another stairwell going up, done in chessboard marble.

"So Professor Trelawney is the careers advisor?"

"Professor Trelawney is Hogwarts' Divinations Professor," Dumbledore said, fiddling with a knot in his beard. "Aside from her work in financial consultancy, crystal orb repair, relationship counselling, property investment, and insurance, she is our resident careers advisor."

"She can predict the future?"

"If only it were so simple." Dumbledore sighed, finally undoing the beard-knot that had been causing him grief and in doing so creating two more.

He asked Ozland to make sure he was standing on a white square, and using a staff that hadn't been in his hand until a moment before, he tapped at the chequered marble floor. Immediately, the square Ozland had been standing on began to separate itself from the rest, accelerating up the stairwell, causing the others around it to fly apart around it, like the tiles on a scrabble board after being violently shook.

The door was ajar. Ozland pushed, and Dumbledore followed.

Professor Trelawney's room was strangely comforting. It was wide and open, but felt curiously snug. Purple draperies, curtains and carpets were everywhere, and in the centre, there were about fifty evenly-spaced, circular tables – each with a kettle. It smelt strongly of cinnamon and oranges.

"Ah, Albus," came a voice from across the room. "What can I do for – no, of course, Master Dwimmersmith is here to have his potential career paths examined."

"Uncanny as always," Dumbledore said, his eyes twinkling, and then in a lowered, conspiratorial voice, "were it not for the fact that I scheduled this appointment – "

" – four weeks ago," Professor Trelawney said, "and I foresaw that you would schedule the appointment so I scheduled an appointment for you to schedule the appointment."

Dumbledore shook his head. "As I said, uncanny. Ozland, this is – ah, I've already introduced you – and Sybill, this is – hmm, I see introductions will not be necessary." At Ozland's uncertain look, he added: "Across from the tables, behind the curtain."

He then promptly vanished in a ball of fire (Ozland decided to put off thinking about that one for the moment).

The Divination Professor seemed to pride herself on her oddness, like most of the wizarding world. She had thick glasses that gave her eyes a bulbous look, and cultivated frizzy hair. Moreover, she was sitting in front of fifty cups of tea, all of them in the process of being stirred and refilled by some unseen mechanism. As Ozland sat himself down in front of her desk, he noticed her eyes were flitting from cup to cup, as if checking each one. After some time, she began furiously scribbling down notes on parchment.

"Tasseomancy – tea-reading, of course," Professor Trelawney said, profoundly, "but you already know that. You're wondering what I'm doing with fifty cups of tea, and you're also wondering how they're being stirred."

A long, dramatic pause followed this remark. "The answer to your second question is a combination of the runic transform of the Refilling Charm, which is fueled by Hogwarts' leylines, and a generic motion-effect Charm adapted to stir the tea. Would you like to know the answer to the first question, then?"

He nodded.

The Divination Professor told him to pick up a cup, take it in his left hand, and move it in a circle rapidly three times from left to right.

"Should I drink it now, then?"

"Don't be silly," she said, tapping the rim of the cup with her wand. The liquid immediately disappeared, leaving only light-green water at the bottom along with scattered fragments of tea leaves. "Now," the witch pointed to a series of little black clumps stuck to the side, "what do these look like to you?"

Ozland paused, considering. "A boat . . . and a cloud, oh and that one looks like a fox."

Professor Trelawney stared at him, in an odd, piercing way, as if she had divined some deep and unknowable truth and decided not to say it aloud. "Very good," she said slowly, "now, any of these symbols can represent any number of things. The fox is an opportunity, or a friend who has turned against you, the boat is a journey – physical or metaphorical, and the cloud is changing circumstances . . . usually for the worse. The meaning is amplified by the positional relations between the symbols, you see – impressive, certainly, but not useful or actionable."

"I see," Ozland said, barely keeping up. "But why would clumps . . . no, I have a better question – why would a clump of leaves that looked like a fox have anything to do with opportunity?"

"Why do fairy-tales have evil stepmothers? Why do stories have beginnings, middles, and ends? Why do birds fly in flocks, and why are buildings made of bricks? The fox is a unit, a symbol of the deep subconscious, and it is only through contextualising it, renewing it, as a symbol of opportunity or betrayal that it acquires a meaning, Mr. Dwimmersmith."

"But you could contextualise the fox to mean anything," he argued.

Professor Trelawney smiled for the first time he had seen her. "Precisely. Now, suppose a blacksmith wanted to know where he ought to set up shop in France? Would 'opportunity' and 'betrayal by a friend' suit his purposes?"

"I wouldn't think so." Ozland leaned forward, thinking intensely. "Oh, so you're constructing new interpretive systems. Ones that need more than one cup."

"Precisely. What you see in front of you, Mr. Dwimmersmith, is a General Diviner." The Divination Professor sat back, seeming utterly satisfied, and then suddenly frowned. "Or, at least, the beginnings of one. I suspect a few thousand more cups will be needed. The issue, unfortunately, is any system I design, I'll have to be able to remember in complete detail while I'm stirring the teacups – but a Universal Diviner would require a very large system indeed."

"That's quite the conundrum," Ozland said sympathetically. "Will this set-up be able to tell me about what career I should choose?"

"Career?" Professor Trelawney said, blankly. "Oh, yes." She lazily motioned with her hand, and a sheet of paper flew from the ceiling. "I'll just need to refresh," she murmured, scanning over the paper. "It's the trouble, every meaning-system has to be simultaneous and relational, so you won't ever be able to extract a simple English sentence from a Specific Diviner – all the tea-leaves settle down into clumps at the same time, after all. And each symbol-combination has to relate to the meaning somehow."

"Hmm."

Professor Trelawney put the paper down, closing her eyes and seeming to concentrate. "Twenty-five, up, stir, drain," she commanded. Half of the cups rose into the air and did exactly that. What was left was an enormous marbled pattern that stretched across a table.

The witch peered at the cups, consulted the notes, and looked up once more.

There was a long silence.

"Oh, dear. This has never happened before."

#######